music
音楽
applause
拍手
thank you
ありがとう
This is September's Feast of Knowledge
これは9月の知識の饗宴です
This topic is very attractive
この話題はとても魅力的です
One topic is related to the history of medicine
トピックの 1 つは医学の歴史に関連しています。
I actually wanted to hear this
実はこれが聞きたかったのです
speech
スピーチ
It just so happened that our other vice president was in charge of this
たまたま、もう一人の副社長がこの件を担当していました
Vice President Huang
黃副院長
He's abroad so he asked me to host
彼は海外にいるので私にホストを頼んだ
I am honored to be the host of this feast of knowledge
この知識の饗宴の主催者になれることを光栄に思います
this time
この時
The speaker is Dr. Lei Xianglin
講演者は雷香林博士です
he has very
彼はとても持っています
unique background
ユニークな背景
It is
それは
Associate Researcher of the Prohibition Institute in the Institute of Prohibition Institutes is also
禁酒研究所の禁酒研究所准研究員も務めています。
Associate Professor at the Institute of Technology and Society, Yangming University
陽明大学科学技術社会研究所 准教授
He graduated from the Department of Chemistry, National Taiwan University, and is also my alma mater and alma mater.
彼は国立台湾大学化学科卒業であり、私の母校であり母校でもあります。
so he is
だから彼は
this is mine
これは私のものです
Junior is equal to a generation
ジュニアは世代に等しい
Then at the University of Chicago he switched to history
その後シカゴ大学で歴史学に転向した
He also has a master's degree in chemistry from the University of Chicago
彼はシカゴ大学で化学の修士号も取得しています。
The University of Chicago is also my alma mater
シカゴ大学は私の母校でもあります
Or my doctorate over there is also my junior
あるいは、向こうの博士号も私の後輩です
So it's rare to have this background of chemistry and history
したがって、このような化学と歴史の背景を持つことはまれです
But it's also about chemistry
でもそれは化学の話でもある
I'm a helper to learn chemistry Chemistry publicity
化学学習のお手伝いです 化学広報
Many of us in the courtyard are chemistry students
中庭にいる私たちの多くは化学の学生です
Like the seniors or juniors in my past department
前の部署の先輩や後輩のように
I don't know in the life science group
ライフサイエンスグループではわかりません
There are quite a few who used to be directors
元監督だった人もたくさんいる
There are vice presidents
副社長もいるよ
But I'm honored for the first time
でも初めて光栄です
Now one is from chemistry to history
今は化学から歴史へ
published numerous articles
多数の記事を出版
But one article worth mentioning is
しかし、言及する価値のある記事が 1 つあります。
Nilidonky No Horse Medicine in the struggle over China's modernity
中国の近代化をめぐる闘争におけるニリドンキーの馬薬なし
published by the university
大学が発行した
Published in 2014
2014年発行
This one once won the American Medical History Society class
これはかつてアメリカ医学史協会のクラスで優勝したことがある
William Welch Medal in 2016
2016 年ウィリアム・ウェルチ・メダル
Then I also won this award in the Humanities and Social Sciences Special Book Award of Academia Sinica
そして、中央研究院の人文社会科学特別図書賞でもこの賞を受賞しました。
It was responsible for promoting the openness of Taiwan's science and technology and social academic network
台湾の科学技術と社会学術ネットワークのオープン化を促進する責任を負っていました。
this is a three year plan
これは3年計画です
From 2001 to 2004
2001 年から 2004 年まで
The next long-term participation was initiated by Taiwanese scholars
次の長期参加は台湾の学者によって開始された
The international academic journal edited by him is called East Asian Science Technology and Society
彼が編集する国際学術誌は「東アジア科学技術と社会」
This is an International Journal
これは国際ジャーナルです
is published by Duke University
デューク大学から出版されています
In 2016, this year began to take over the
2016年、今年は
Please warmly welcome the protagonist Dr. Lei
主人公のレイ博士を温かく迎え入れてください
Thank you, Dean Dr. Lei, for your introduction
学部長のレイ博士、ご紹介いただきありがとうございます
I would like to thank the hospital for giving me this opportunity to make this report with you
このような報告をする機会を与えてくださった病院に感謝します。
Of course, I would also like to thank everyone advanced
もちろん、先達の皆さんにも感謝したいと思います
and colleagues and friends
そして同僚や友達
After a day of hard work is over
一日の苦労が終わったら終わりです
Only dare to listen to this speech after get off work
このスピーチは仕事を終えてから聞く勇気を持ってください
When you see the topic of today's speech
今日のスピーチのテーマを見ると、
It should be a bit of a surprise
ちょっとした驚きになるはずです
Because these two topics and subtopics
これら 2 つのトピックとサブトピックがあるため、
Looks like it's only set to quite different things
かなり異なるものに設定されているだけのようです
The main title is the name of Du Congming's Chinese meaning to study
メインタイトルは杜崇明の中国語の勉強するという意味の名前です
Seems like a very specific case
非常に特殊なケースのようです
That is to say, of course it is Mr. Du Congming, who everyone knows
つまり、もちろん誰もが知っている杜聡明さんです。
but only a very small part of his research
しかし、彼の研究のごく一部にすぎません
sounds like a very case study
まさにケーススタディのようですね
But the subtitle Traditional Medicine and Modernity in East Asia
しかし副題は「東アジアの伝統医学と近代性」
sounds like a big topic
大きな話題のようですね
and it seems to have a lot of meaning and probing
それには多くの意味と疑問が含まれているようです
This is indeed a design for my speech today
これはまさに今日の私のスピーチのデザインです
I want to talk about a specific individual
特定の個人について話したい
Maybe many people will care
もしかしたら気になる人も多いかもしれない
and has not been adequately answered
そして十分な答えが得られていない
an issue that is debated even today
今日でも議論されている問題
So maybe it is not the same as the goal of our knowledge experiment today.
したがって、それは今日の知識実験の目標と同じではないかもしれません。
What I share with you today is not so much knowledge
今日私が皆さんにシェアするのは、それほど多くの知識ではありません
Of course there is knowledge
もちろん知識はあります
But to a greater extent, it may be to share with you
しかし、より大きな意味で、それはあなたと分かち合うことかもしれません
Questions that are still debated today
今日でも議論されている問題
then please let me try first
それでは、まず試してみさせてください
Let’s start from solving the big problem of the subtitle
サブタイトルの大きな問題を解決することから始めましょう
The question I want to share with you today
今日皆さんと共有したい質問
What Vice President Liu said just now meant that
劉副大統領が今言ったことの意味は、
I graduated from the Department of Chemistry
私は化学科を卒業しました
indeed so
確かにそうです
from a certain point of view
ある観点から見ると
This is the issue that we are concerned about in this speech or my research
これがこの講演や私の研究で私たちが懸念している問題です
It's actually a very simple question.
実はとても単純な質問なのです。
It's a question that a chemistry student would also think of
化学の学生でも考えそうな問題ですね
That is to say, all kinds of traditional East Asian knowledge about nature
つまり、自然に関するあらゆる種類の伝統的な東アジアの知識です。
From 1900 to present
1900 年から現在まで
The world has been completely replaced by modern science
世界は完全に現代科学に取って代わられた
Why Only Traditional Medicine Is the Only Accident
なぜ伝統医学だけが事故になるのか
exception
例外
Why Chinese medicine is still active in our life today
なぜ中国医学は今でも私たちの生活の中で活躍しているのか
and even spread back to the rest of the world
そして世界の他の地域にも広がりました
Come to think of it, this is indeed a rather strange phenomenon.
考えてみれば、これは実に奇妙な現象である。
right
右
That is to say, a student who has never studied history
つまり、歴史を勉強したことがない学生です。
also start to feel curious
好奇心を持ち始める
from a certain angle
ある角度から
I'm a historian trying to answer
私は答えようとしている歴史家です
that is
あれは
what kind of historical process
どのような歴史的過程があるのか
This led to such a peculiar phenomenon
それがこんな奇妙な現象を引き起こした
We want to know the course of history
歴史の流れを知りたい
more importantly i think
もっと重要なことは私が思う
Many people here will care
ここにいる多くの人が気にするだろう
What is the significance of this historical phenomenon
この歴史的現象にはどのような意味があるのでしょうか
Does it mean that East Asia is still far behind?
東アジアはまだはるかに遅れているということですか？
Or does it mean there are other possibilities?
それとも別の可能性があるということでしょうか？
This should be a further question
これはさらに質問する必要があります
that's my original
それは私のオリジナルです
A naive question that I think everyone will agree on
誰もが同意すると思う素朴な質問
But many simple questions that everyone cares about
しかし、誰もが気にする多くの単純な質問
Historians are unlikely to be able to solve
歴史家が解決できる可能性は低い
So I'm going to
だから私はそうするつもりです
Use two specific historical scenes to present a
2 つの特定の歴史的シーンを使用して、
A specific question that we are better able to answer than historians
歴史家よりも私たちの方がよく答えることができる具体的な質問
The first of these two historical scenarios takes place in 1925
これら 2 つの歴史シナリオのうちの最初のシナリオは 1925 年に起こります。
This is Dr. Sun Yat-sen trying at Union Hospital in Beijing.
これは北京の連合病院で努力している孫文博士です。
Before he tried it, he already knew that liver cancer was incurable.
彼はそれを試す前から、肝臓がんが不治の病であることをすでに知っていました。
Then what about that time
じゃあその時はどうだろう
Whether he should take traditional Chinese medicine before dying
死ぬ前に漢方薬を服用すべきかどうか
become a matter of national concern
国家的な関心事になる
Everyone wants to know the one who overthrew the Qing Dynasty
誰もが清朝を打倒した人物を知りたがっている
leader of the revolution
革命の指導者
Did he take Chinese medicine when he was weakest?
一番弱っているときに漢方薬を飲むのでしょうか？
He himself has medical training
彼自身も医療訓練を受けています
right
右
That means he was at his weakest at the end of his life
それは彼が人生の終わりに最も弱かったことを意味します
Abandoned what he believed in science and modernity
彼が信じていた科学と近代性を捨てた
while taking traditional Chinese medicine
漢方薬を服用しながら
So the newspapers report every day
それで新聞は毎日報道します
Let's see if he will give in
彼が屈服するかどうか見てみましょう
that was the situation
それが状況だった
what about later
後はどうですか？
among those who care
世話をする人々の間で
Another Lu Xun who also studied medicine in Japan
同じく日本で医学を学んだもう一人の魯迅
After Sun Yat-sen passed away, he once wrote that
孫文が亡くなった後、彼はかつてこう書いた。
He once heard that Sun Yat-sen refused to take traditional Chinese medicine
孫文が漢方薬の服用を拒否したと聞いたことがある
In fact, Sun Yat-sen took Chinese medicine in the end
実際、孫文は最終的に漢方薬を服用しました
In addition, he was consigned to the Xiehe Hospital for taking traditional Chinese medicine.
さらに、漢方治療のため謝和病院に委託された。
Ask him to move out of the hospital before he can take Chinese medicine
漢方薬を服用する前に病院から出てもらうように頼んでください
But once Lu Xun heard that Sun Yat-sen refused to take traditional Chinese medicine
しかし、魯迅は孫文が漢方薬の服用を拒否したと聞いたことがあります。
He said the news that Sun Yat-sen refused to take traditional Chinese medicine
孫文が漢方薬の服用を拒否したというニュースについて彼は言った
No less than his lifetime revolutionary cause touched me
彼の生涯の革命的な大義が私に感動を与えたのです
Even the overthrow of the Qing Dynasty has not moved him so much
満州国清の打倒でさえ彼をそれほど動かさなかった
He still doesn't take Chinese medicine at this time
彼は現時点ではまだ漢方薬を服用していません
That makes him feel really touched
それは彼に本当に感動を与える
So you can imagine that
だからそれは想像できる
at this point in time
この時点で
Whether to take traditional Chinese medicine or not is not a small problem of personal health
漢方薬を服用するか否かは、個人の健康に関わる小さな問題ではありません
Rather, it represents a major issue in the development of a country
むしろ、それは国の発展にとって大きな問題です
so everyone will be very concerned
だからみんなとても心配するだろう
And Lu Xun gave him such a high importance
そして魯迅は彼を非常に重要視した
This is in 1925 and 1926
これは 1925 年と 1926 年のことです
but after half a century
しかし半世紀を経て
This meaning is almost reversed
この意味はほぼ逆になります
still in the same hospital
まだ同じ病院にいる
Still at Peking Union Medical College Hospital
まだ北京連合医科大学病院にいる
It's one that's heavily supported by the Rockefeller Foundation.
それはロックフェラー財団によって多大な支援を受けているものです。
The most advanced hospital in East Asia at that time
当時東アジアで最も先進的な病院
that is very famous
それはとても有名です
Just to visit with Nixon
ニクソン氏を訪問するためだけに
Interviewed by a New York Times reporter
ニューヨーク・タイムズ記者によるインタビュー
James Reston
ジェームズ・レストン
He had an operation and was admitted to this hospital
彼は手術を受けてこの病院に入院した
At that time the hospital had been renamed
その時に病院名が変わりました
Anti-land hospital
対陸病院
Then after he went in
それから彼が入った後
Received some weeks of treatment during surgery
手術中に数週間の治療を受けた
He found it very miraculous
彼はそれがとても奇跡的だと感じた
He later interviewed some of the patients inside
その後、彼は院内の患者数名にもインタビューした
And feel the amazing effect
そして驚くべき効果を実感してください
So he was later in the New York Times
それで彼は後にニューヨーク・タイムズに載った
published an article
記事を公開しました
Where is the special article?
特集記事はどこにありますか？
It also starts from today's special article
今日の特集記事からも始まります
Only Americans have heard the term AcuPuncture
AcuPunctureという言葉を聞いたことがあるのはアメリカ人だけです
Syndromal fever
症候群性発熱
Well James Reston knows very well
ジェームス・レストンはよく知っています
how ironic this thing is
これはなんて皮肉なことだろう
When the hospital was established
病院設立当時
the Logefeller Foundation
ローフェラ財団
In order to introduce the spirit of science into China
中国に科学の精神を導入するために
and built up
そして築き上げられた
Unexpectedly, after receiving treatment here, he
意外なことに、ここで治療を受けた後、彼は
And believe that China has created a
そして中国が
Symptoms unknown to other modern medicine
他の現代医学では知られていない症状
And combine the old medical treatment with the new
そして、古い医療と新しい医療を組み合わせます。
medical together
一緒に医療
It seems that China has developed another
中国がまた開発したらしい
Effective medical treatment that the world does not know
世界が知らない効果的な医療
To expand a little
少し拡張するには
It's like another kind of modernity
それは別の種類の現代性のようなものです
so it feels a strong irony
だから強い皮肉を感じます
And this also triggered the whole
そして、これは全体の引き金にもなりました
The real origins of the alternative medical craze
代替医療ブームの本当の起源
Then the two scenes I'm showing you now
それでは、今お見せする 2 つのシーン
50 years apart in the same hospital
50歳も離れて同じ病院にいる
Almost the entire Chinese medicine or traditional medicine
ほぼすべての漢方薬または伝統医学
Relationship to Science and Relationship to Modernity
科学との関係と現代性との関係
reversed
逆転した
If in order to let everyone feel more deeply
そしてみんなにもっと深く感じてもらうために
How big is this reversal
この逆転はどれくらい大きいのか
Let's look at another gentleman's lecture
別の紳士の講義を見てみましょう
This is Fu Sinian, who once served as the president of National Taiwan University after the war
戦後、国立台湾大学の学長を務めた傅思念氏です。
He said that I would not consult Chinese medicine even when I was dying.
たとえ死にそうになっても漢方には相談しない、と。
I feel that if I don't, I'm sorry for my education.
そうしないと教育に申し訳ないと感じます。
So he has a very strong stance
だから彼は非常に強い姿勢を持っています
And what's more
そしてさらに
In 1934 he published an essay
1934年に彼はエッセイを出版した
He said
彼は言った
The most shameful, hateful and breathless thing in China now is
今、中国で最も恥ずべき、憎しみに満ちた、息も詰まる出来事は、
It's not a bandit exchange, it's not a foreign exchange
それは盗賊取引所ではありません、それは外国為替取引所ではありません
It should be the so-called dispute between Chinese and Western medicine
いわゆる中医学と西洋医学の論争のはずだ
This is almost the same as what Lu Xun said
これは魯迅の言っていることとほぼ同じです。
At that time, the Northeast was completely occupied by the prison army.
当時、北東部は捕虜軍によって完全に占領されていました。
But he thinks it's more shameful than such a foreign exchange
でも彼はそんな外国為替よりも恥ずかしいことだと思っている
There is still the so-called dispute between Chinese and Western medicine
中国医学と西洋医学の間には、いわゆる論争が依然として存在します。
he said why
彼はその理由を言いました
Because they think they are advocating waiting
彼らは待つことを推奨していると思っているからです
common sense of science
科学の常識
still in chaos
まだ混乱の中にある
let alone more complicated things
もっと複雑なことは言うまでもありません
To this day, I still come there to compete for Chinese and Western medicine
今でも私は中医学と西洋医学を競い合うためにそこに来ています。
Wouldn't it make people all over the world think that the Chinese are a kind of human beings from another world?
それは世界中の人々に、中国人は別の世界から来た一種の人間であると思わせるのではないでしょうか？
The school that has been in operation for 40 years still cannot break away from this medieval stage
創立40年を迎える学校は未だに中世の段階から抜け出せない
Doesn't it make people feel that the future of education is still the same
教育の未来はまだ変わらないと人々は感じませんか
he said very serious things
彼はとても深刻なことを言いました
Especially here is a special mention of waiting
特にここでは待機について特筆します
is what I call the concept of modernity
それは私が近代性の概念と呼ぶものです
then i want here
それならここが欲しいです
Here you can in this seemingly simple sentence
この一見単純な文で次のことができます。
Actually there are many
実はたくさんあるんですよ
I explained why the discussion on China and the West was so important at that time
当時中国と西側に関する議論がなぜそれほど重要だったかを説明しました
An important matter that is not allowed to be decided by individuals
個人で決めることが許されない重要事項
because it actually touches on a debate about modernity
それは実際に現代性についての議論に触れているからです
How should I put it, we just looked at, for example, the first element
なんというか、たとえば最初の要素を見ただけです。
The meaning of modernity basically means that
近代性の意味は基本的に次のことを意味します
We determine Europe's experience in modern development
私たちは近代開発におけるヨーロッパの経験を判断します
And there seems to be a general trend
そして全体的な傾向があるようです
feel that all people in the world
世界中のすべての人が感じていること
Feel like the whole world is going the same way
世界中が同じ方向に進んでいるように感じる
Everybody's heading for the nation-state, capitalism, the industrial revolution
誰もが国民国家、資本主義、産業革命に向かっている
even the acceptance of science and so on
科学の受け入れなどでも
Therefore, in this universal direction of common development
したがって、この共通の発展の普遍的な方向に沿って、
If you still have to develop another contingency alone
それでも別の不測の事態を一人で開発しなければならない場合
It's as if you've become different from everyone else
まるで他の人とは違うようになったような
Not in line with the trend of universal development
普遍的な発展の傾向に沿っていない
Second, if you are really different from others
第二に、あなたが他の人と本当に違う場合
Your difference is not what we call multiculturalism today
あなたの違いは今日私たちが多文化主義と呼ぶものではありません
Different cultures have different values
文化が違えば価値観も違う
People will tell you that what you're talking about is familiar to me
あなたが話していることは私にとってよく知られたことだと人々は言うでしょう
Just a few hundred years ago we were in the medieval stage
ほんの数百年前、私たちは中世の段階にありました
We advocate the same medicine during the dark period
私たちは暗い時代に同じ薬を提唱します
So this difference is not considered a value
したがって、この差は値として考慮されません
Instead it would clearly be seen as a previous period in history
むしろ、それは明らかに歴史の前の時期として見られるでしょう
And going a step further
そしてさらに一歩進んで
This why is that in such a European experience
これがヨーロッパでの経験の中でなぜそうなるのか
they will get the perception
彼らは認識を得るでしょう
Some even Europeans feel
ヨーロッパ人でも感じる人はいる
Developments from the 17th century are not just new phases of history
17 世紀からの発展は単なる歴史の新たな段階ではありません
is an unprecedented stage
前例のないステージです
We know the truth about the world like never before
私たちはこれまでにないほど世界についての真実を知っています
That is to say, it is completely different from the past
つまり、今までとは全く違うのです
In this sense, the most representative
そういう意味で最も代表的なのは、
It's modern science
それは現代科学です
Wait until our Newtonian almanac, wait until the Newtonian almanac is invented
ニュートン年鑑ができるまで待って、ニュートン年鑑が発明されるまで待ってください
We don't feel like we're just entering a new phase
新しい段階に入ったばかりだとは感じていません
It's the feeling that everyone in the past was wrong
過去の人たちは皆間違っていたという感覚だ
We know the truth about nature like never before
私たちはこれまでにないほど自然についての真実を知っています
and thus bring us to the front
そして私たちを前に連れて行きます
premodern people were completely different
前近代の人々は全く異なっていた
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
In fact, science has been around throughout our modern history
実際、科学は私たちの現代史を通じて存在してきました。
My research unit is modern history
私の研究単位は近現代史です
it has a very special meaning
それはとても特別な意味を持っています
That is to say, if we talk about the political system
つまり、政治システムについて言えば、
female role
女性の役割
In other words, the relationship between the state, politics and religion
つまり、国家、政治、宗教の関係
If there is room for debate among cultures
文化間に議論の余地があるなら
It shouldn't be hard for everyone to question
誰もが質問するのは難しいことではないはずです
Science has the highest generality
科学は最も一般性が高い
And we clearly see the progress of science
そして科学の進歩がはっきりとわかります
and we clearly see
そして私たちははっきりと見ています
There is a very big break between science and the past
科学と過去の間には大きな断絶がある
In the past, not only China had traditional Chinese medicine
かつて、伝統的な漢方薬があったのは中国だけではありませんでした
The West also has their traditional Greek medicine
西洋にもギリシャの伝統医学がある
But those can be completely given up
しかし、それらは完全にあきらめることができます
without any hesitation
何の躊躇もなく
we know those are wrong
私たちはそれらが間違っていることを知っています
Those have only historical value
それらには歴史的価値しかありません
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
science as modernity
現代としての科学
That is to say that science makes us feel most clearly
つまり、科学は私たちに最も明確な感覚を与えてくれるのです
developed in Europe
ヨーロッパで開発された
Many of these systems have developed
これらのシステムの多くは、
is of universal value
普遍的な価値がある
And it deserves a system that the people embrace from a new perspective
そしてそれは、新しい視点から人々が受け入れるシステムに値する
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
Original European Modern History Experience
オリジナルのヨーロッパ近代史体験
It is no longer just a historical experience
それはもはや単なる歴史的な経験ではありません
and became a normative concept
そして規範的な概念となった
or in this era
あるいはこの時代に
Some would say the concept of civilization
文明の概念だと言う人もいるだろう
people of other nationalities
他の国籍の人たち
There is no need to examine their
彼らを調べる必要はない
Every part of historical and cultural knowledge
歴史的および文化的知識のあらゆる部分
you know you should start with
から始めるべきだとわかっています
Europe's historical experience and development direction
ヨーロッパの歴史的経験と発展の方向性
as a development direction
開発の方向性としては
because that's the way to go
それが進むべき道だから
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
you can see
見ることができます
in this sense
この意味で
Just now Fu Sinian would feel
今、フー・シニアンはこう感じるだろう
The Importance of Discussion about China and the West
中国と西側についての議論の重要性
Because suppose once you admit
なぜなら、一度認めてしまうと仮定してみてください
you are in east asia
あなたは東アジアにいます
your whole european experience
あなたのヨーロッパ全体の経験
they all give up their own
彼らは皆自分自身を放棄します
Pre-Modern Medical Cases
近代以前の医療事件
and you read the same
そしてあなたも同じことを読んでいます
keep another
もう一つ取っておく
self-proclaimed scientific medicine
自称科学的医学
make you different from the whole world
あなたを全世界とは違うものにする
It seems to mean that there are many different possibilities for the development of this world
それは、この世界の発展にはさまざまな可能性があることを意味しているようです
right
右
That's what Fu Sinian said
傅思念氏はそう言った
If you can't even distinguish such a clear thing
そんな明確なことさえ区別できないなら
As for the development of other political aspects of society
社会の他の政治的側面の発展に関しては
There will be countless debates that can take place
無数の議論が起こる可能性がある
so for them
だから彼らにとっては
It's a matter of life and death
それは生死に関わる問題だ
That's why there was so much debate
だからこそあれほど議論があったんだな
But at that time, in order to ask questions about Chinese medicine
しかしその時、漢方について質問するために
triggering the resignation of the chief executive at the time
当時の最高責任者の辞任を引き起こした
So it should be regarded as the truth of nuclear four in the 1920s and 2030s.
したがって、これは 1920 年代と 2030 年代の核 4 の真実とみなされるべきです。
At that time, this was a very political theory
当時、これは非常に政治的な理論でした
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
I started from Su Pu's question just now
先ほどのSu Puさんの質問から始めました
When I turn this question into a specific historical question
この質問を特定の歴史的な質問に変えると
we can say
と言えます
It is how Chinese medicine has developed within half a century
半世紀で中国医学はこうして発展した
sworn enemy of modernity
近代性の不倶戴天の敵
what we think must be excluded
私たちが除外しなければならないと考えているもの
and transformed into Chinese exploration and modernity
そして中国の探検と現代性へと変容した
The most concrete symbols and tools
最も具体的なシンボルとツール
That's what I was going to ask
それが私が尋ねようとしていたことです
And one of my specific historical questions
そして、私が特に歴史的に疑問に思っていることの 1 つは、
It's also what Vice President Liu just mentioned
それは劉副大統領が先ほど述べたことでもあります
I'm writing a book about it
それについて本を書いています
The Chinese name is "Fei Aluminum Fei Ma"
中国名は「飛アルミ飛馬」。
Medicine and China's Modernity Controversy"
医学と中国の近代性論争」
But what?
でも何？
I don't want to come with you today
今日は一緒に行きたくない
talk about the content of this book
この本の内容について話す
On the one hand, there is no way to do it in one speech.
一方で、一度のスピーチでそれを行う方法はありません。
on the other hand
一方で
So I want to change a perspective to share with you
そこで視点を変えて皆さんと共有したいと思います
possible problems in this history
この歴史の中で考えられる問題
And I hope you feel that in this history
そして、この歴史の中でそれを感じていただければ幸いです
Contains more complex issues than we originally thought
当初考えていたよりも複雑な問題が含まれている
still interesting
まだ興味深い
but also
だけでなく、
still under debate
まだ議論中
And it's worth taking a serious look at him
そして彼を真剣に見てみる価値がある
That
それか
This brings me to the main title of my speech today
これが今日の私のスピーチのメインタイトルになります
it is me
それは私です
i started from a
私はから始めました
related but otherwise distinct context
関連しているが別個のコンテキスト
It is the context of Mr. Du Congming
杜聡明氏の文脈です
To answer the historical development just now
今の歴史的発展に答えるために
The problem
問題
Mr. Du Congming, everyone should be the most familiar scientist
杜聡明さん、誰もが最も身近な科学者であるべきです
He Taiwan's first doctor of medicine
台湾初の医学博士
The first and third term of National Taiwan University School of Medicine
国立台湾大学医学部前期・後期
The third dean
3代目学部長
And founded Kaohsiung Medical College
高雄医科大学を設立
on my story
私の話について
he has a very important
彼にはとても重要なことがあります
an effort
努力
It was him from 1928 to 1929
1928年から1929年までは彼だった
Published an investigation on the research methods of Chinese Medicine
中医学の研究方法に関する調査結果を発表
At that time he had just returned to Taiwan
その時彼は台湾に戻ったばかりだった。
The legend says that he built a Han medicine hospital
漢医学病院を建てたという伝説がある
and cause a
そして、
Than Mr. Qiyuan criticized him
斉源氏が彼を批判したよりも
As a result, Mr. Du was published in Taiwan Ming Pao
その結果、杜氏は台湾の明報に掲載されました。
Published 31 texts
31冊のテキストを出版
like this
このような
Then a total of 31 articles were published in half a year
その後、半年で合計 31 件の記事が公開されました
Then there are a total of 60,000 words
すると合計60,000語になります
So it's hard for everyone to imagine now
だから今は誰もが想像するのが難しい
is you in a
あなたはいますか
Detailed scientific debate published in major large newspapers
主要な大手新聞に掲載された詳細な科学的議論
It talks about a lot of history of science, chemical terms, etc.
科学の歴史、化学用語などについてたくさん話します。
But it took half a year
でも半年かかった
Just one of mine is very important today
今日の私の一つだけがとても重要です
The topics I will share with you later
後で共有するトピック
It's from this article
この記事からです
that's not only it
それだけではありません
And Mr. Du Congming
そして杜聡明さん
What about during the Japanese occupation and after the war?
日本統治時代や戦後はどうだったのでしょうか？
Twice established Chinese medicine hospital
二度設立された漢方病院
The first time was from 1928 to 1929 as I just said
一回目は今言ったように 1928 年から 1929 年にかけてでした。
The second time was 1946, soon after the war
2度目は戦後間もない1946年。
And it was not approved twice
そして二度も承認されなかった
and the second time
そして二回目
It was after changing the principal after 228
228以降校長が変わってからでした。
It should be Mr. Fu Sinian who put this
これを載せたのはFu Sinian氏のはずです
To set up the program of Chinese Medicine Therapy Department
中医学療法学科のプログラムを立ち上げる
canceled
キャンセル
Then what about Du Congming
では杜崇明はどうだろうか
He also wanted to promote research in this area after the war
彼は戦後もこの分野の研究を推進したいと考えていました。
Not only during the Japanese occupation period
日本統治時代に限らず
He said I was in Taipei City University and National Taiwan University School of Medicine
彼は私が台北市立大学と国立台湾大学医学部にいると言いました。
For 20 years, I have taught students the history of traditional Chinese medicine
20年間、私は学生たちに伝統的な中国医学の歴史を教えてきました。
Pharmacology of Traditional Chinese Medicine and Shanghan Theory
中医学の薬理学と上漢理論
make students get an idea
生徒にアイデアを出させる
I hope they can read Chinese medicine books
彼らが中国医学の本を読めるようになるといいですね
But recently, the Academic Affairs Office of National Taiwan University School of Medicine told me
しかし最近、国立台湾大学医学部教務事務局が私にこう言いました。
I don't have time, I can't schedule this class
時間がないので、このクラスのスケジュールを立てることができません
So I terminate this handout
したがって、この配布資料を終了します
I created Kaohsiung Hospital by myself
高雄病院は自分で作りました
I'm going to teach in it myself
私自身がその中で教えるつもりです
Later he created Gao Yi
その後、彼はGao Yiを作成しました
he did teach
彼は教えました
Also published several books
著書も何冊か出版
So we can see that
それでわかります
his insistence on the matter
その問題に対する彼の主張
It's actually a lot of effort
実際には大変な労力です
And many friends also know
そして多くの友人も知っています
He has three famous studies
彼には3つの有名な研究がある
Regarding opium snake venom and traditional Chinese medicine
アヘンヘビ毒と漢方薬について
right
右
Then this is the famous third item
続いてこちらが有名な３品目です
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
I mentioned this to you
私はあなたにこのことを話しました
The secret of Chinese medicine research means
中医学研究の秘密とは
Du Congming, the leader of medical modernity in Taiwan
杜聡明、台湾の近代医療のリーダー
Why do you support the pre-modern for a long time
なぜ昔から前近代を支持するのか
Traditional East Asian Medicine
東アジアの伝統医学
Now Mr. Du Congming's book
さて、杜聡明氏の本
We have a lot of books in Cobo
コボにはたくさんの本があります
But it seems that few of us come to discuss
しかし、議論しに来る人はほとんどいないようです
this problem
この問題
and more importantly
そして更に重要なことに
not only he supports
彼がサポートするだけではなく
And his career is on his shoulders
そして彼のキャリアは彼の肩にかかっています
persistently viewed as outdated
頑固に時代遅れとみなされている
acts against science
科学に反する行為
And because of this midterm he never had the means to build
そして、この中間選挙のせいで、彼には建設する手段がまったくありませんでした
The Han medicine he wants to establish
確立したい漢方医学
So this is what I call today
今日はこれをこう呼びます
Du Congming is well-known for his research on traditional Chinese medicine
杜聡明は伝統的な中国医学の研究で有名です
Then I try to share with you
それから私はあなたと共有しようとします
I mean why on earth would he want to do this?
つまり、一体なぜ彼はこんなことをしたいのでしょうか？
That is the main axis of my report to you below.
それが、以下の私のレポートの主軸です。
I'll take off my coat then. I'm sorry.
それではコートを脱ぎます。ごめんなさい。
I hope you all find this to be a puzzle.
皆さんもこれがパズルだと思っていただければ幸いです。
In this case, everyone will look forward to hearing some answers.
この場合、誰もがいくつかの答えを聞くのを楽しみにしています。
well that
まあそれは
The simplest way is to say
最も簡単な方法はこう言うことです
Let's start from just now and let me explain his example a little bit
今から始めて、彼の例を少し説明しましょう
From the concept of modernity we just talked about
先ほど話したモダニティの概念から
Well, in terms of the current concept
さて、現在のコンセプトで言えば、
This is the example we just mentioned
これは先ほど述べた例です
In terms of the concept of modernity we just talked about
先ほど話したモダニティの概念に関して言えば、
In fact, you are interested in pre-modern things
実は前近代的なものに興味があるのですね
Pre-Modern should be able to raise without hesitation
プレモダンなら迷わず上げられるはず
right
右
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
It should be clear that people can be divided into
人々は次のように分類できることは明らかです。
Modern Science and Traditional Conservation
現代科学と伝統的保存
So we just looked at, say, from
それで、たとえば、から見てみただけです
Cong Sun Yat-sen Lu Xun Fu Sinian
宋孫文 魯迅フー・シニエン
They all think they are on the side of the modern
彼らは皆、自分たちは現代の側にいると思っている
But if we compare modernity and science
しかし、現代と科学を比較すると、
They should be far behind Du Congming
彼らは杜聡明よりはるかに遅れているはずだ
right
右
In terms of his academic qualifications
彼の学歴に関して言えば、
They should be much worse than Du Congming
彼らは杜聡明よりもずっと悪いはずだ
puzzling is to say
不可解なことは言うことです
Du Congming seems to have adopted a
杜聡明は、
Viewed as a pro-traditional medical stance, at least at the time
少なくとも当時は伝統医学擁護の立場とみなされていた
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
Let's not talk about the answer to this mystery now
この謎の答えについては今は話さないでおこう
The case of Du Congming is very worthy of our careful consideration
杜聡明の事件は注意深く検討する価値がある
Because it's actually pretty easy for us to find other supportive people
なぜなら、私たちが他に協力してくれる人を見つけるのは実はとても簡単だからです
But if other supporters previously
しかし、以前に他のサポーターがいた場合、
we can easily say
私たちは簡単に言うことができます
they have no scientific mind
彼らには科学的思考がありません
they have a vested interest
彼らは既得権益を持っています
or they themselves have no science
あるいは彼ら自身に科学がない
do not understand
理解していない
Science right?
科学ですよね？
But Du Congming, you can't say that about him
しかし、杜聡明、彼についてはそんなことは言えません
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
His case exemplifies a very large
彼のケースは非常に大きな問題を例示している
combine two irreconcilable elements
2つの相容れない要素を組み合わせる
thus presenting a great deal of inner tension and creativity
したがって、多大な内的緊張と創造性を示します
So before I solve the problem
だから問題を解決する前に
I hope you can feel
感じていただければ幸いです
an inherently interesting aspect of the matter
問題の本質的に興味深い側面
But if we think about it further
しかし、さらに考えてみると
How to understand Du Congming
杜聡明をどう理解するか
when i was doing research in the city
街で取材していたとき
I think of what a friend told me
友人が私に言ったことを思い出します
At that time, Taipei 101 was the tallest building in the world.
当時、台北101は世界で最も高い建物でした。
Then this friend is a foreign friend
そうするとこの友達は外国人の友達です
he told me
彼は私に言った
But it doesn't seem to feel
でもそれは感じられないみたい
He is the tallest building in the world
彼は世界で一番高い建物です
Later he told me that the reason was because
後で彼はその理由を教えてくれました。
There are no other tall buildings nearby
近くに高い建物はありません
so if you go to new york
それでニューヨークに行くなら
You see the so-called sports building first
いわゆるスポーツ棟が最初に見えます
That's 1901 high
それは1901高です
you can compare one by one
1つずつ比較できます
Do you know how tall that building is?
あの建物の高さはどれくらいか知っていますか？
If there are no other tall buildings next to Taipei 101
台北101の隣に高い建物がない場合
You can't see the uniqueness of this building
この建物の個性が見えない
where is he high
彼はどこにいますか
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
Thanks to this long article by Du Congming
Du Congming 氏のこの長い記事のおかげで
Long essays up to 60,000 words
60,000ワードまでの長文エッセイ
It should be the entire Japanese occupation period
日本統治時代全体のはずだ
even postwar Taiwan
戦後の台湾でも
rare heavyweight scientist
稀代の重鎮科学者
An important document for Chinese medicine and Chinese medicine
漢方・漢方医学にとって重要な文書
so for me
だから私にとって
A big challenge is to say
大きな課題は次のとおりです。
How do I find points to compare
比較するポイントを見つけるにはどうすればよいですか
so that we can compare
比較できるように
His uniqueness and where his ideas lie
彼のユニークさと彼のアイデアの所在
So the middle part of the speech below
以下のスピーチの中間部分
all i want to do is
私がやりたいのはそれだけです
I want to put it in multiple historical contexts
複数の歴史的文脈に置きたい
Let everyone understand his possible uniqueness
誰もが彼のユニークな可能性を理解できるようにする
The first is to put it in Japan
まずは日本に置くこと
In the context of Japan
日本の文脈で言えば
The second is to put it in the context of Chinese and Western theory of truth in the period of the Republic of China
2つ目は、中華民国時代の中国と西洋の真理理論の文脈に置くことです。
just mentioned
先ほど述べた
Third I'm going to put it in
3番目に入れてみます
In the context of the development of Western medical history
西洋医学の歴史の発展の文脈で
Especially an experimental therapeutic novelty
特に実験的な治療上の新規性
Another Chinese medicine hospital that he mentioned
彼が言及した別の漢方病院
finally i called juicing
最後にジュースに電話しました
There is a very clever research method
非常に巧妙な調査方法があります
There is also a very unique place
とてもユニークな場所もあります
I call it the reverse method of research
私はそれを逆研究法と呼んでいます
Later I will explain from these five directions
この5つの方向から後ほど説明します
its special place
その特別な場所
The first is Japanese
1人目は日本人です
modernity with hygiene
衛生的な現代性
many friends know
多くの友人が知っています
Japan began to accept the West
日本は西洋を受け入れ始めた
The starting point of Western scientific case knowledge
西洋科学の事例知識の出発点
Anatomy of Genpaku Mita
就是三田玄白解剖
The right one he can't understand at all
正しいものは彼にはまったく理解できない
Dutch Anatomy Book Anatomy
オランダの解剖学の本 解剖学
The structure of the human body as taught by Chinese medicine
中医学が教える人体の仕組み
It's all wrong, right?
それは全部間違っていますよね？
So he started working hard to learn Dutch
それで彼はオランダ語を学ぶために一生懸命働き始めました
Then translate this book into Japanese
それからこの本を日本語に翻訳してください
It becomes the dismantling new book
解体新書になります
This also became the starting point for the Japanese to become interested in blue studies
これは日本人が青学に興味を持つきっかけにもなりました。
Published in 191774
191774 年に発行
this is a very early period
これは非常に初期の時期です
And let's just talk about it
それについて話しましょう
know Japan's experience in medicine and medical science
日本の医学と医学の経験を知る
In contrast to China
中国とは対照的に
So in the Opium War
それでアヘン戦争では
Didn't China's self-improvement movement also start to introduce blood sucking?
中国の自己改善運動でも吸血が導入され始めたんじゃなかったっけ？
But at that time they didn't think
しかし、当時彼らは考えていませんでした
Medicine is a particularly important science
医学は特に重要な科学です
In fact China began to accept medical
実際、中国は医療を受け入れ始めた
Far more than it accepts chemistry, mining and other knowledge
化学、鉱業、その他の知識をはるかに超えて受け入れます
until the beginning of the 20th century
20世紀初頭まで
Manchuria became a transfer point only after it belonged
満州は属国になって初めて中継地となった
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
Japan's acceptance of blood-sucking experience is in sharp contrast with China
日本の吸血体験の受け入れは中国とは対照的だ
The starting point of Japan is related to medical anatomy
日本の原点は医療解剖学に関係する
And later the Japanese enlightenment master Fukuzawa Yukichi
そして、その後の日本の啓蒙の達人、福沢諭吉。
The school he himself originally attended was also the school run by Lan Yi.
彼自身が元々通っていた学校もラン・イーが経営する学校だった。
If you read his biography now,
今彼の伝記を読むと、
You'll see him with the students who were there at the time
彼が当時そこにいた学生たちと一緒にいるのを見るでしょう
Let's take the opportunity to look forward to the former Han doctor
この機会に前漢の医師に期待しましょう
I think they are very unscientific and outdated
それらは非常に非科学的で時代遅れだと思います
in other words
言い換えると
Contemporary Japanese Enlightenment Master
現代日本啓蒙マスター
his own enlightenment experience
彼自身の悟りの体験
It's just that traditional medicine is wrong
伝統医学が間違っているだけです
should be discarded
捨てるべきだ
And the more progressive development of this meaning
そして、この意味がより進歩的に発展すると、
That is to say, to become not only
つまり、
It became an important part of Japan's self-belief that it entered the modern era later.
それは、日本が近代に突入したという日本の自尊心の重要な部分となった。
Medicine has become an important way for Japan to successfully join the West and modern times
医学は日本が西洋と近代にうまく参加するための重要な手段となっている
And it also became a later combined with the colonial policy
そして、それは後に植民地政策と結合することにもなった
This is a classic work of our Asian studies
これは私たちのアジア研究の古典的な作品です
hygienic modernity
衛生的な現代性
It is pointed out in this work
この作品でも指摘されてる
It later became the core strategy of Japan's colonial expansion to Korea, Manchuria, Taiwan and China
それは後に、朝鮮、満州、台湾、中国への日本の植民地拡大の中核戦略となった。
is not only a core experience of Japan
それは日本の核となる経験だけではありません
And it became an important means of later colonial expansion
そしてそれは後の植民地拡大の重要な手段となった
so that we later heard that
それで私たちは後でそれを聞きました
Goto Shinpei
後藤新平
It is also one of the very important promoters
非常に重要なプロモーターの1つでもあります
Then wrote the National Sanitation Principles
その後、国家衛生原則を書きました
It is also the close connection between medical care and hygiene
医療と衛生も密接な関係にあります
Closely integrated with the governance of the country and colonial governance
国の統治と植民地統治と密接に統合されている
And this is actually felt by people in the colonies
そしてこれは植民地の人々も実際に感じていることです
So on New Year's Day in 1925, Taiwan's Ming Pao editorial
そこで1925年の元旦、台湾の『明報』社説はこう言った。
After 30 years of Japanese occupation, he said
30年間の日本占領を経て、彼はこう言った。
We are now looking back at the achievements of the Governor-General in the past 30 years
私たちは今、過去 30 年間の総督の功績を振り返っています。
Our most commendable from beginning to end
最初から最後まで私たちの最も賞賛すべきもの
It's about sanitary facilities.
衛生設備についてです。
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
This is a stronger
こっちの方が強いよ
That is to say, Du Congming is in the context of Japan
つまり、杜聡明は日本の文脈の中にあるということだ。
should be more strongly affirmed
もっと強く肯定されるべきだ
Western Medicine and Hygiene
西洋医学と衛生学
And it's of very high importance to his
そしてそれは彼にとって非常に重要です
Du Congming is indeed so
杜聡明は確かにそうだ
He himself is not only a product of this
彼自身もこれの産物であるだけではありません
And therefore he thinks that
したがって、彼はこう考えます
implemented in Taiwan
台湾で導入された
The Doctrine that Let Han Physicians Dissolve Naturally
漢医師自然解散主義
It is a policy that is extremely adapted to the requirements of the times
極めて時代の要請に適応した政策である
He is sure of this policy
彼はこの方針を確信している
That Japanese
あの日本人
Part of Modern Medicine and Hygiene
現代医学と衛生学の一部
You may be more familiar
あなたの方がよく知っているかもしれません
What you may not be familiar with is that
あまり馴染みのないことかもしれませんが、
What about the other side?
反対側はどうですか？
Beginning to recognize in modern Japan
現代日本でも認識され始めている
While Dr. Han was wrong
ハン博士は間違っていたが
But they have a
しかし、彼らは
very different history
非常に異なる歴史
Only recently came out two recent books stating that
つい最近、次のようなことを述べた最近の本が 2 冊出版されました。
After Materia Medica Okaki was introduced to Japan
在本草岡木傳入日本之後
Indeed Japan developed very close to modern natural history
実際、日本は現代の自然史に非常に近い形で発展してきました。
Natural History
自然史
Darwin was a natural history scholar, right?
ダーウィンは自然史学者でしたよね？
That is to say, beyond the tradition of traditional herbal medicine
つまり、伝統的な漢方薬の伝統を超えて
And the beginning equals that Japan is somewhat self-sufficient
そしてその始まりは日本がある程度自給自足していることに等しい
developed a research tradition close to a natural history like Darwin's
ダーウィンのような自然史に近い研究の伝統を発展させた
and developed a realistic image
リアルなイメージを開発しました
That is to say, so at that time it was
つまり、当時はそうだったのです
Just like the pictures on the poster I gave you today, there are many
今日お渡ししたポスターの写真のように、たくさんあります
Everyone knows that the picture of Materia Medica Okagi does not have marble needles attached at all.
マテリア・メディカ・オカギの絵にはマーブルの針がまったく付いていないことは誰もが知っています。
As far as the picture is concerned with Materia Medica, it has always been very crude
マテリア・メディカの絵に関する限り、それは常に非常に粗雑なものでした
But we see very beautifully in the Japanese tradition
しかし、私たちは日本の伝統をとても美しく見ています
very close to our modern graph
私たちの現代のグラフに非常に近い
And this is combined with realism
そしてこれはリアリズムとも組み合わされています
Then this becomes a very important self-identity in the development of Japanese science
そして、これは日本の科学の発展において非常に重要な自己アイデンティティになります。
It is through this that they are almost independent
これにより、彼らはほぼ独立した状態になります
independently developed their scientific traditions
独自に科学的伝統を発展させた
and not only in natural history
自然史だけではありません
Later, this herbal tradition means
この薬草の伝統は後にこう言われています。
Changjing Changyi
長京チャンイー
It is the founder of modern Japanese medicine
近代日本医学の開祖です
That's also the discoverer of ephedrine.
それはエフェドリンの発見者でもあります。
So it is equal to this one of the University of Tokyo, Japan
つまり、これは日本の東京大学のものに相当します
Founder of the Department of Pharmacy
薬学部の創設者
He is based on the research on crude drugs of Chinese medicine
漢方の生薬研究をベースにしている
And he was the one who extracted the ephedrine first.
そして最初にエフェドリンを抽出したのは彼だった。
That
それか
Du Congming himself studied at Kyoto University
杜聡明自身も京都大学で学んだ
also a doctor of pharmacy
薬学博士でもある
His teacher is also a master of pharmacy
彼の先生は薬学の修士でもあります
So all this means
つまり、これはすべて意味します
After combining with this herbal medicine in Japan
日本でこの漢方薬を配合したところ
developed not a total negation
発展は完全な否定ではない
But on Materia Medica and modern science
しかし、マテリアメディカと現代科学については
have a deep bond
深い絆がある
So Du Congming said
そこで杜聡明は言った。
Japan since the Meiji Restoration
日本自從明治維新以後
Scientific research on the crude drugs of Galaxy
銀河の生薬に関する科学的研究
Make the greatest contribution to the world
世界に最大限の貢献をする
So everyone hear here
だからみんなここで聞いてね
might feel like saying
と言いたくなるかもしれない
Du Congming's words sound like
杜聡明の言葉は次のように聞こえる。
very simple
とてもシンプルな
But in fact, this sentence means more than we
しかし実際には、この文は私たち以上の意味を持っています
than he said
彼が言ったよりも
He is too humble
彼は謙虚すぎる
Because it sounds like you might just think that
と思ってしまいそうなので
Japanese for Materia Medical
マテリアメディカルの日本語
Herbal research is better
ハーブ研究のほうが優れている
So just contribute the most in the world
だから、世界で最も貢献するだけです
Not only that
それだけでなく
When it comes to the era we are talking about now
今私たちが話している時代になると
In fact, modern western medicine
実は現代西洋医学では、
don't think at all
まったく考えないでください
in traditional herbal
伝統的なハーブで
can find something worth researching
研究する価値のある何かを見つけることができる
and it starts early
そしてそれは早く始まります
The one on the left is a professor at Harvard University
左の人はハーバード大学の教授
professor of medicine
医学教授
In 1870 he said
1870年に彼は言いました
If we take all Materia Medical
マテリアメディカルを全て取ると
If you throw them all into the sea
全部海に捨てたら
humanity has nothing to lose
人類には失うものは何もない
It just might kill the fish
それは魚を殺すかもしれない
In other words, Materia Medica
つまり、マテリアメディカ
no research value at all
研究価値がまったくない
the man on the right
右の男
This is what it was like in 1870
1870年はこんな感じでした
By 1924
1924年までに
This man's name is John Grant
この男の名前はジョン・グラントです
he is beijing
彼は北京です
Founder of Public Health Department of Xiehe Hospital
謝和病院公衆衛生局の創設者
Often referred to as the father of public health in China
中国の公衆衛生の父と呼ばれることが多い
He is also a famous hero in public health
彼は公衆衛生界の有名な英雄でもあります
That is to say, it affects later
つまり後々影響する
that
それか
Let me not go too far
あまり遠くへ行かないように
He was sent to Union Hospital
彼はユニオン病院に送られた
When sent by Rockefeller's foundation to visit Japan
ロックフェラー財団から日本訪問に派遣されたとき
He saw that Chinese medicine research is being done everywhere in Japan
彼は、日本のいたるところで漢方薬の研究が行われているのを見ました。
He felt very backward
彼はとても後ろ向きな気持ちになった
Then criticize the study
そしてその研究を批判する
That's why I want to tell you that
だからこそ、あなたに伝えたいのです
If we take time back to this era
この時代に時間を戻せば
What Du Congming said
杜聡明の言ったこと
is too modest a statement
控えめすぎる発言です
As far as Japan was not only affected by Japan at that time
当時の日本だけが被害を受けたわけではないのに
The influence of German pharmacy
ドイツの薬局の影響
make a great contribution
多大な貢献をする
And this contribution was at the time
そしてこの寄稿は当時
From an American point of view
アメリカ人の視点から見ると
It's an outdated and weird one at all.
それはただ時代遅れで奇妙です
Why do you remember to study this
なぜこれを勉強することを覚えているのですか
worthless research
価値のない研究
and therefore
したがって
So like I just told you
だから今言ったように
When we arrived at Peking Union Medical College Hospital
北京連合医科大学病院に到着したとき
What about the Union Hospital at that time?
当時のユニオン病院はどうだったのでしょうか？
just to say
ただ言うために
I'm going to show you the Union Hospital
コンコルド病院というものを見せたい
Now it was called John Hopkins in China
現在、中国ではジョン・ホプキンスと呼ばれています
Rockefeller's Foundation
ロックフェラー財団
to make a concrete proof
具体的な証拠を作るために
building a genetic body
遺伝的な身体を構築する
Let you know what is scientific research
科学研究とは何かを教えてください
So everything is a parody of John Hopkins
つまり、すべてはジョン・ホプキンスのパロディです
only two things are not
そうでないものは 2 つだけです
one thing is his roof
一つは彼の屋根です
that is, they feel
つまり、彼らは感じます
since here
ここから
I can't teach you everything
すべてを教えることはできない
to show my respect for you
あなたに敬意を示すために
That's why we put a Chinese roof
だから中国製の屋根を付けたんだ
Then this became the later
それからこれは後者になりました
Characteristics of Chinese Modern Architecture
中国の近代建築の特徴
Now you go to Beijing and see a lot of big roofs
今北京に行くと、大きな屋根を持った人がたくさんいます。
And many people now feel that this is very
そして多くの人が今、これはとても大変なことだと感じています。
What is not ideal is related to this development system
理想的ではないのはこの開発体制にあります
Another Rockefeller Foundation
もう一つのロックフェラー財団
There was a lot of internal debate at the time
社内ではかなりの議論があった
is whether they want to set up a
をセットアップしたいかどうかです。
Department of Pharmacy to study Materia Medica
マテリアメディカを学ぶ薬学部
Which means they are very reluctant to do this research
つまり、彼らはこの研究を行うことに非常に消極的です
but they say they come here
でも彼らはここに来ると言っています
Everyone says they think there's a gold mine in there.
誰もがそこに金鉱があると思うと言います。
So there's a really big debate among them
彼らの間では本当に大きな議論が起こっています
everyone can know
誰もが知ることができる
You can imagine what Du Congming said just now.
杜聡明が今言ったことは想像できるでしょう。
What a unique situation at the time
当時としてはなんとも特殊な状況だった
Definitely not to say that everyone is researching
全員が研究しているとは決して言えません
And very important is a unique influence of Japan
そして非常に重要なのは日本独自の影響です
Then some interesting history developed here.
その後、ここで興味深い歴史が生まれました。
But I don't want to go far
でも遠くには行きたくない
I just want to come back and say something
戻ってきて何か言いたいだけです
I do an interpreted result
解釈結果を行います
Explain that some friends will think that
友達の中にはそう思う人もいるだろうと説明する
what you say
あなたが言うこと
you've solved it
あなたはそれを解決しました
It is Du Congming who can do research and medicine
研究と医学ができるのは杜聡明です
Just because it's a product of Japanese tradition, right?
それは日本の伝統の産物だからですよね？
Do you feel this way
そう感じますか
largely
大体
but if so you can't explain
しかし、もしそうなら説明できません
Then why does it suggest
では、なぜそれが示唆されるのか
The Governor's Palace has never accepted it, right?
総督府は一度も受け入れていないですよね？
so I largely
だから私は主に
What I want to say in this paragraph is to say
この段落で言いたいことは、
to a very large extent
非常に広い範囲で
Du Congming proposed this research
杜聡明がこの研究を提案した
It is indeed a product of Japan
まさに日本の製品です
and at the time
そしてその時
is a very unique research tradition
非常にユニークな研究の伝統です
But our riddle isn't over yet
でも私たちの謎はまだ終わっていない
because if so
もしそうなら
what he does is he is
彼がやっていることは彼そのものだ
Easy to learn with the scene
場面に合わせて学びやすい
it's him
それは彼です
words learned in college
大学で習った単語
That's no reason why he can't continue in Taiwan
それは彼が台湾で続けられない理由にはならない
right
右
So I haven't solved my name yet
だからまだ名前は解けてない
then I'll go to another place first
それならまず別の場所に行きます
Said to put him in the second vein
彼を第二の静脈に入れると言われた
That's the one
それだ
On the Truth between China and the West in the Republic of China
中華民国における中国と西側の真実について
A very in the period of the Republic of China
まさに中華民国の時代
Very comparable to Du Congming
杜聡明に非常に匹敵する
He is the super sinner in the history of Chinese medicine
彼は中国医学史上の超罪人です
Is Yu Yan
ユ・ヤンです
This man is a graduate of a university in Osaka
この男性は大阪の大学の卒業生です
Then in 1929 when he
そして1929年に彼は
It was the first committee of the National Government to establish the Ministry of Health.
これは保健省を設立した最初の中央政府委員会であった。
Raise waste paper for medical treatment
医療用古紙を回収する
To remove obstacles to medical hygiene
医療衛生上の障害を取り除くため
like this case
このケースのように
Very big teacher plagiarized Japan
とても偉い先生が日本を盗作した
Just to waste paper traditional medical treatment
紙を無駄にするだけの伝統医療
detonated the theory of truth between China and the West
中国と西側の間の真実の理論を爆発させた
wait until after 1949
1949年以降まで待ってください
that is
あれは
because of this whole thing
このすべてのせいで
he plays a very important role
彼は非常に重要な役割を果たしています
So after 1949
それで 1949 年以降
After Mao Zedong began to support Chinese medicine
毛沢東が中国医学を支持し始めてからです。
TCM Policy During the Nationalist Government Period
国民政府時代の中医学政策
are called an oppressive Chinese medicine
抑圧的な漢方薬と呼ばれています
Pneumonia Pneumonia Pneumonia Drug Storage Policy
肺炎 肺炎 肺炎 医薬品保管政策
So he alone represents the entire force of oppression
つまり彼だけが抑圧の力全体を代表している
so this is a
これは
People who are often mentioned in the history of modern Chinese medicine
現代中国医学の歴史でよく言及される人々
Then he and Du Congming actually have a lot of similarities
そして、彼と杜聡明には実際に多くの類似点があります
They also study in Japan
彼らは日本にも留学しています
And there are people in Japan
そして日本にも人がいる
Du Congming's memoir video mentioned more than once
杜聡明の回想録ビデオが複数回言及された
pneumonia
肺炎
And then they also advocate the study of medical history
そして彼らは病歴の研究も提唱しています
And almost at the same time sparked debates about traditional medicine
そしてほぼ同時に伝統医学についての議論を引き起こした
Du Congming was from 1928 to 1929
杜聡明は1928年から1929年まで
Fisherman is the spring of 1929
漁師は1929年の春
They also oppose the theory of Yin-Yang and Five Elements
彼らは陰陽論と五行説にも反対します。
and both advocate the scientific approach to the study of traditional medicines
どちらも伝統医学の研究に対する科学的アプローチを提唱しています
As you can imagine, it's only natural
ご想像のとおり、それは当然のことです
Based on the Japanese tradition I just mentioned, right?
先ほど述べた日本の伝統を踏まえたものですよね？
But there is one big difference between the two
しかし、この2つには大きな違いが1つあります
It is the fisherman who advocates the preservation of lung medicine
肺医学の保存を主張する漁師です
and the fisherman said
そして漁師は言いました
During the Republic of China
中華民国時代
People who are eligible for research do not want to study traditional Chinese medicine
研究対象者は中医学を勉強したいわけではない
why
なぜ
because
なぜなら
If we follow the American tradition we just talked about
先ほど話したアメリカの伝統に従えば、
Nogfi's genetic society is unwilling to try to study it
ノグフィの遺伝学会はそれを研究しようとする気はない
Then you're a really top-notch trained man
それならあなたは本当に一流の訓練を受けた人です
Why study this one people think is a Dying Science
人々が瀕死の科学だと考えているこのことをなぜ研究するのか
right
右
So everyone is unwilling to study
だからみんな勉強する気がないんだよ
However, many Chinese medicine practitioners say that they need to study
しかし、多くの漢方医は勉強が必要だと言います。
But they don't have a laboratory at all, they don't have the ability
しかし、彼らには研究室がまったくなく、能力もありません
They are not eligible for research
彼らは研究の対象にはなりません
That's what Yu Yan said
ユウヤンがそう言ってた
From this point of view
この観点から見ると
Du Congming constitutes an exception to what Yu Yan said
Du Congming は Yu Yan の発言の例外となる
Du Congming undoubtedly has the qualifications for research
杜聡明は間違いなく研究の資格を持っている
And he is serious about studying traditional Chinese medicine
そして彼は伝統的な中国医学の勉強に真剣に取り組んでいます
Not only does he want to study traditional Chinese medicine, but also his research methods
彼は伝統的な中国医学を学ぶだけでなく、その研究方法も学びたいと考えています。
It's not about saving money
それはお金を節約することではありません
Have a public talk with Du Congming
杜聡明と公開会談する
I am a pharmacologist
私は薬学者です
Mainly, of course, drug research
もちろん主に医薬品の研究です
It's just that this plan also hopes to consider
ただ、この計画も検討していきたいと思っています
systematically carry out non-pharmacological
非薬理学的を体系的に実行する
Research on Chinese Medicine
中医学の研究
And it is also surprising to say that
そして、こう言うのも驚きです
The words written by Du Congming are often very
杜聡明の書いた言葉は、多くの場合非常に優れています。
The step-by-step writing method that reveals the truth
真実を明らかにするステップバイステップの書き方
But he would jump out and say
でも彼は飛び出してこう言いました
I dare not say anything about the advantages and disadvantages of Chinese medicine and Western medicine
漢方と西洋医学のメリット・デメリットについてはあえて言いません。
only in the case of bone setting
ボーンセッティングの場合のみ
I dare say bone setting is much greater than western surgery
あえて言えば、骨の調整は西洋の外科手術よりもはるかに優れています
So Du Congming seems to be interested in Chinese medicine, including bone setting and snake medicine
蘇杜聡明は整骨術や蛇薬などの中国医学に興味があるようです
a lot of further knowledge, right?
さらに詳しい知識がたくさんありますよね？
So from this perspective, it is quite different from the language.
この観点から見ると、言語とはまったく異なります。
Now let me come back to the unresolved issue I just said about Japanese tradition
さて、日本の伝統は未解決の問題であるという先ほどの話に戻ります。
I said he is very much a product of Japanese tradition
私は彼はまさに日本の伝統の産物だと言いました
But if that's the case, we can't understand
でもそうだとしたら私たちには理解できない
Why has his ambition never been supported?
なぜ彼の野心は支持されなかったのでしょうか?
That's because in that sense
そういう意味ではそうだから
Not a product of Japanese tradition
日本の伝統の産物ではない
To the third one, I will talk about the development of modern medicine, experimental therapeutics
3つ目は現代医学の発展、実験的治療法についてお話します。
Du Congming in 1928
杜聡明、1928年
After he was sent by the Governor's Mansion to study in Europe and the United States for two years and four months, he came back
総督公邸から2年4ヶ月の欧米留学を経て帰国
Written by European and American medical inspection talks
ヨーロッパとアメリカの医療検査協議によって書かれたもの
He just talked about the results of his study tours in various places over the past two years.
この２年間の各地への研修旅行の成果を語ったところです。
He found that therapeutics is an independent lecture in universities in Europe and America
彼は、ヨーロッパやアメリカの大学では治療学が独立した講義であることを発見しました。
80% especially in France
特にフランスでは80％
But in Japanese therapeutics
しかし日本の治療法では
no individual lectures yet
まだ個別の講義はありません
So when I say it, everyone thinks it's weird
だからそれを言うとみんな変だと思うよ
In fact, the Japanese medical system
実は日本の医療制度は、
Take Xi, Japan and Germany as a model
習氏、日本、ドイツをモデルとする
Only import the unique German medical tourism
ドイツ独自の医学トラベルサイエンスのみを輸入
Therapeutic lectures that the French system says are very progressive
フランスのシステムは非常に進歩的だと主張する治療的講義
no
いいえ
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
Du Congming, he is now going to propose
杜聡明、彼は今プロポーズするつもりです
When experimental therapeutics is used to study Chinese medicine
中国医学の研究に実験的治療法が使用される場合
It was not a natural extension of his studies at Kyoto University
それは京都大学での彼の研究の自然な延長ではありませんでした
but his newly learned
しかし、彼は新しく学んだ
Newly learned what I just learned in Europe and the United States
欧米で学んだばかりのことを新たに学んだ
The result of hitting the oil
オイルを打った結果
And we can see clearly from where he hit the oil
そして、彼がオイルに当たった場所からはっきりとわかります
because the founder of experimental therapeutics
実験的治療法の創始者だから
Rockford
ロックフォード
Chair of the Department of Pharmacy at John S. Hopkins University
ジョン・S・ホプキンス大学薬学部長
He organized the American
彼はアメリカの組織を組織した
Society of Pharmacy and Experimental Therapeutics in 1908
1908 年の薬学実験療法学会
Du Congming used to go to his laboratory when he hit oil
杜聡明は石油にぶつかったとき、よく自分の研究室に通っていました。
and say
そして、言います
This is one of the three American scientists he most admires
彼は彼が最も尊敬する 3 人のアメリカ人科学者の 1 人です
so from here
だからここから
Everyone read his article
誰もが彼の記事を読んだ
In fact, he repeatedly proposed that experimental therapeutics
実際、彼は実験的な治療法を繰り返し提案しました。
Rather than talk about medicine in general
医療全般について話すのではなく、
Not about animal experiments, not about chemical research
動物実験や化学研究についてではありません
It is about experimental therapeutics combined with clinical human research
臨床人間研究と組み合わせた実験的治療法に関するものです
So it's not about him
だからそれは彼のことじゃない
Achievements of Learning at Kyoto University
京都大学での学びの成果
And, wait until he is going back to Taiwan
そして、彼が台湾に戻るまで待ってください
He just wrote that he thought of two things that could be done with experimental therapeutics
彼は実験的治療法でできることを 2 つ考えたと書いたところです
Study available in Taiwan
台湾で受講可能
One is the de-addiction treatment of duck slices
一つはアヒルのスライスの依存症治療です。
The second is the experimental therapeutics of traditional Chinese medicine
2つ目は、伝統的な中国医学の実験的治療法です。
So neither of those are direct extensions of his training in Japan.
したがって、どちらも日本での訓練の直接の延長ではありません。
And we can see that that is
そして、それが
Two of his three famous studies relate to his latest learning
彼の 3 つの有名な研究のうち 2 つは、彼の最新の学習に関連しています
Experimental Therapeutics Related
実験的治療学関連
And he is and we can see from today
そして彼はそうであり、今日からそれがわかります
He advocated this study
彼はこの研究を提唱した
Not only for the study of traditional Chinese medicine
中医学の研究だけでなく
to promote new research methods
新しい研究手法を推進する
He is also for the development of experimental therapeutics in Taiwan
彼は台湾における実験的治療法の開発にも尽力しています。
Development of therapeutics that did not exist in the Empire of Japan at that time
当時の大日本帝国には存在しなかった治療薬の開発
and self-transformation as an experimental therapist
そして実験療法士としての自己変革
away from what he was supposed to learn
彼が学ばなければならなかったことから離れて
It is only because of his identity as a scholar that he deliberately chooses research topics with local advantages
学者として、彼は地元の利点を持つ研究テーマを意図的に選択しました
So what is his choice?
それで彼の選択は何でしょうか？
It's actually a two-way
実は双方向なんです
On the one hand, he chooses one that he thinks will be useful for research
一方で、彼は研究に役立つと思うものを選択します
Research methods of traditional Chinese medicine
中医学の研究方法
his new method
彼の新しい方法
On the other hand, this theme with local advantages
一方で、地元のメリットを活かした今回のテーマは、
Because Westerners don't come to do research like this, right?
だって西洋人はこんな研究しに来ないですよね？
so be him again
それでまた彼になってください
Became a force for him to introduce the experimental therapy case and transform himself into an experimental therapist
実験療法の事例を紹介し、実験療法士に変身する原動力となった
So this chooses this two-way
したがって、これは双方向を選択します
Not only for Chinese medicine but also for the development of science
漢方だけでなく科学の発展にも貢献
Well everyone knows that
まあ誰もがそれを知っています
Du Congming imagined that he would return to Taiwan to do two things
杜聡明は台湾に戻って2つのことをするだろうと想像した
Then there was a completely different development
その後、全く違う展開があった
one is
一つは
Taiwan's Governor's Office was criticized by the Taiwan People's Party for the Japanese policy of duck slices
台湾総督府は日本のアヒルのスライス政策について台湾人民党から批判された
Quickly accepted Du Congming's idea
杜聡明の考えをすぐに受け入れた
Established the Taiwan Roots Institute of the Governor-General of Taiwan
台湾総督府台湾ルーツ研究所を設立
So he used experimental therapeutics to do the duck filming thing
そこで彼は実験的な治療法を使ってアヒルの撮影を行った
Immediately paid to achieve
達成するとすぐに支払いが行われます
From the time he wrote this article
彼がこの記事を書いた時から
in less than a year
1年以内に
another one
もう一つ
Another one is to say
もう一つはこう言うことです
It has never been possible to study sweat medicine
汗の医学を研究することはこれまで不可能でした
took a completely different path
全く違う道を歩んだ
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
You can now see a
これで、
develop
発展
and not just to study a new discipline
新しい分野を勉強するだけではありません
Du Congming also said to establish a new research institute
杜聡明は新たな研究機関を設立するとも述べた
khan medical hospital
カーン医療病院
That's what I said at the time
あの時私がそう言ったのです
the harshest criticism of his critics
彼の批評家に対する最も厳しい批判
He said
彼は言った
this must be evil
これは悪いことに違いない
If you want to study sweat medicine
汗医学を学びたいなら
sweat medicine
汗の薬
Then continue the original research method
その後、独自の調査方法を継続します
You just need to set up a pharmacology lab
薬理学研究室を設立する必要があるだけです
right
右
conduct animal experiments
動物実験を行う
why do you want a hospital
なぜ病院が欲しいのですか
Since you want a hospital
病院が欲しいから
That must be hoping to rebuild a
それはきっと再建を望んでいるに違いない
The two medical systems that confront each other between Khan and current medical care
カーンと現在の医療制度の間で対立する2つの医療制度
So this is one of his biggest criticisms
これが彼の最大の批判の一つです
But from Du Congming's point of view
しかし、杜聡明の視点から見ると、
That's what he learned by crashing
それが彼がクラッシュによって学んだことだ
and reflects what other people don't understand
他の人が理解していないことを反映しています
his heart
他的他的用心
Khan Medical Research Hospital
カーン医学研究病院
Primarily a research institution
主に研究機関
Twenty beds will basically witness the specific kind of patients we need for our experimental therapy class research
20 台のベッドは基本的に、実験療法クラスの研究に必要な特定の種類の患者を観察します。
do not accept any patients
患者を受け入れないでください
In fact, you can tell from his physical experience
実際、彼の身体的経験からそれがわかります。
This is the same as when he was at the Rockefeller Institut in New York at the time
これは彼が当時ニューヨークのロックフェラー研究所にいたときと同じです
Met the famous Japanese scientist Hideshi Noguchi who had a close relationship
親密な関係にあった日本の有名な科学者野口英史と出会う
where the host of the rockefeller institute
ロックフェラー研究所のホストがいる場所
Create the Rockefeller Institut as a new research institution
新たな研究機関としてロックフェラー研究所を設立
According to a medical historian
医学史家によると
At a time when most hospitals in the United States are still trying to get basic lab facilities
米国のほとんどの病院が依然として基本的な検査設備を確保しようとしている時期に
Simon Flexner is the director of the Rockefeller Genetic Society
サイモン・フレクスナーはロックフェラー遺伝学会の理事です
presents an almost utopian vision
ほぼユートピア的なビジョンを提示する
Ultimately a hospital is a laboratory
結局のところ、病院は研究所です
So the criticism of Du Congming just originated
杜聡明に対する批判はまさに始まったばかりだ
In fact, it happened to be what Du Congming wanted to surpass.
実際、それは杜聡明が超えようとしたものでした。
He established a will with the goal of research
彼は研究を目的とした遺言書を作成した
The two are one and two two are one
二つは一つ、二つは一つ
Then Du Congming said, I know none of you have heard of it.
すると杜聡明は、「皆さんは誰も聞いたことがないでしょう。」と言いました。
But this kind of hospital
でも、こういう病院って
Does exist
ある
not only in new york
ニューヨークだけでなく
Also present at the School of Tropical Medicine in London
ロンドンの熱帯医学大学院にも在籍
Also present at the affiliated hospital of the School of Tropical Diseases of the University of Hamburg
ハンブルク大学熱帯病学部付属病院にも勤務
So it not only has to mention a new discipline
したがって、新しい分野について言及する必要があるだけではありません
it will have a new research facility
新しい研究施設ができるだろう
Then it is worth saying a little bit here, that is,
それから、ここで少し言う価値があります。つまり、
Du Congmin wants to set up a Chinese medicine hospital
杜聡民は漢方病院の設立を望んでいる
Research on Experimental Therapeutics of Chinese Medicine
中医学の実験的治療法の研究
Actually very close to the same time
実はほぼ同じ時期に
In the period of the Republic of China, the goals that doctors of traditional Chinese medicine strived for
中華民国時代、中医学の医師が目指した目標
Because at that time people criticized you and said
なぜなら当時人々はあなたを批判し、こう言いました。
The theory of Chinese medicine is unscientific, etc.
中医学の理論は科学的ではない、など。
They all already find it difficult to argue
彼らはすでに議論するのが難しいと感じています
so they feel like
だから彼らは次のように感じます
I'll go first and I don't want to have so many scientific and philosophical debates with you.
私が先に行きますが、あなたとはあまり科学的、哲学的な議論をしたくありません。
Let's first prove clinically that we are curative
まずは治癒力があることを臨床的に証明しましょう
So they emphasize that the theory of Chinese medicine may not be scientific
そのため彼らは、中国医学の理論は科学的ではない可能性があることを強調しています。
But the treatment is really effective
しかし、治療は本当に効果的です
so as to continuously strive for the establishment of
の確立に向けて継続的に努力するため、
Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital
漢方を使った中医病院
In fact, the Legislative Yuan has passed
実は立法院が可決しました
But later because of the relationship between the Sino-Japanese War
しかしその後、日中戦争の関係で
there is no way to create
作成する方法はありません
But this is indeed the traditional Chinese medicine doctor in the period of the Republic of China
しかし、これはまさに中華民国時代の中医です。
There are also Chinese physicians in Japan who are simultaneously promoting the direction
同時に在日の中医師らが進めている方向性もある
I hope to build a hospital
病院を建てたいと思っています
So now I'm at the last entry in the multiple histories
これで、複数の履歴の最後の項目に到達しました
On the Research Method of "Tao Xing Adversity"
「陶興逆境」の研究方法について
Du Congming not only wants to introduce a new discipline
杜聡明は単に新しい学問を導入したいだけではない
Establishment of new research institutes
新たな研究機関の設立
And in terms of research methods and procedures
研究方法や手順に関しては、
He's also going to come up with something different
彼もまた何か違うことを考え出すだろう
He said that there are two methods for the research of Chinese medicine
彼は、中国医学の研究には2つの方法があると言いました。
A first analysis of chemical active ingredients in the laboratory
研究室での化学活性成分の最初の分析
Use the method of experimental pharmacology to find out its function and use it in clinic
実験薬理学の手法を用いてその機能を解明し、臨床に応用する
He said another way
彼は別の言い方をした
We use prescriptions for sick people to drink
病気の人が飲むための処方箋を使用しています
Observing the clinical effect first
まずは臨床効果を観察する
Then moved to the research laboratory to investigate the active ingredients and their pharmacology
その後、有効成分とその薬理を研究するために研究室に移動しました。
a good way
良い方法
Then what he said sounds simple
そうすると彼の言ったことは単純に聞こえる
Just to mention two methods
2つの方法を挙げると
But if we put this back into the context of the Republic of China
しかし、これを中華民国の文脈に戻してみると、
is a highly debated
非常に議論の余地がある
A debate on research design that also slams
攻撃も伴う研究デザインに関する議論
Someone even invented a term called
という用語さえ誰かが発明しました。
12345 and 54321
12345 と 54321
how to say
どのように言って
is what they think
それは彼らが考えていることです
Standard research procedure is
標準的な調査手順は、
you first need to know
まず知っておく必要があります
what are you researching
何を研究しているのですか
So you have to extract the active ingredients first
したがって、最初に有効成分を抽出する必要があります
right
右
So at that time
だからその時は
National government started
国家政権発足
When deciding to conduct research on traditional Chinese medicine
中医学の研究をしようと決めたとき
The first is the establishment of the Chinese Medicine Research Office
一つ目は中医学研究室の設置です。
Put it in the Chemistry Department of the Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine
中医病院の化学部門に置いてください
So a lot of research has focused on this step
そのため、多くの研究がこのステップに焦点を当ててきました
in chemical analysis
化学分析では
Many times the composition cannot be found
構成が見つからないことがよくあります
or found the components
またはコンポーネントが見つかりました
No legendary medicinal effect
伝説の薬効なし
So I've been stuck on the first level
それで私は最初のレベルで行き詰まっています
So at that time
だからその時は
As far as many TCM practitioners and those who support them say
多くの中医学実践者と彼らを支援する人々が言う限り、
why don't we come
来ませんか
Do clinical research first
まずは臨床研究を行う
try it on a human
人間で試してみる
but at the time
しかし当時は
highly controversial
非常に物議を醸す
At the time, this was criticized as violating medical ethics.
当時、これは医療倫理に違反すると批判されました。
Just take some medicines that you don't even know the effects and toxicity of the medicines
薬の効果も毒性も分からない薬をただ飲むだけ
use it on people
人に対してそれを使う
Even those who criticize Chinese medicine will quote Su Shi
中国医学を批判する人たちも蘇軾の言葉を引用します。
What Su Dongpo said
蘇東坡が言ったこと
Su Dongpo said to study books, waste paper, study medicine and waste people
蘇東坡は、本を学び、紙を無駄にし、医学を学び、人間を無駄にすると言った。
That is to say, if you want to learn calligraphy, you will need to use a lot of declarations
つまり、カリグラフィーを学びたい場合は、多くの宣言を使用する必要があります
What about you who studied medicine?
医学を学んだあなたはどうですか？
Because you don't know how poisonous it is
どれだけ毒があるか知らないから
You must have ruined a lot of people
きっとたくさんの人をダメにしてしまったんだろうね
It even means that the name must be the one that kills the most
それは、その名前が最も多くの人を殺した人物でなければならないことさえ意味します
we don't know
私たちは知りません
So this approach will be very criticized
したがって、このアプローチは非常に批判されるでしょう
and it's not an accepted practice
そしてそれは受け入れられた習慣ではありません
So what Du Congming just said
杜聡明が今言ったことは
The way he said it very plainly
彼はとてもはっきりとそれを言った
In fact, in this context
実際、この文脈では
is a highly controversial method
非常に物議を醸す手法です
Moreover, Du Congming not only pointed out that this method
さらに、Du Congming はこの方法が次のことであると指摘しただけではありません。
He even specifically pointed out which drugs he felt were the most worthy of research.
彼は、どの薬が最も研究する価値があると感じたかを具体的に指摘しました。
he just said
彼はちょうど言った
For so far, there is no way to extract the active ingredients chemically
これまでのところ、有効成分を化学的に抽出する方法はありません。
But Du Cong has clinically
しかし、Du Cong は臨床的に
Drugs that treat real diseases
病気の治療に効果的な薬
For example Bupleurum and Changshan for treating sadism
たとえば、サディズムを治療するためのBupleurumとChangshan
be the first to conduct more sophisticated experimental therapeutic studies on them
それらに対してより洗練された実験的治療研究を最初に実施する
Make sure the experiment works before going to the lab
研究室に行く前に実験がうまくいくことを確認してください
Perform precision chemistry and biology experiments in reverse
精密な化学実験や生物学実験を逆に実行
this is a very important question
これは非常に重要な質問です
So it's not only talking about
だからそれはただ話しているだけではない
It is such a research method that was criticized at the time
当時批判されたような研究手法です
And maybe you will find it surprising that
そしておそらくあなたは驚くべきことに気づくでしょう
Of the only two examples it cites
引用されている例は 2 つだけですが、
one of the long mountains
長い山の一つ
After 20 years it has been proven that there is
20年経って、あることが証明された
It does work
それは機能します
then this is
それならこれは
was in the 1940s
1940年代にあった
by Chen Guofu who has no medical background at all
医学的知識が全くない陳国福氏によるもの
You may have heard of him
あなたも彼のことを聞いたことがあるかもしれません
Chen Lifu
チェン・リフ
We are in almost every TCM
ほぼすべての TCM に含まれています
Chen Lifu's calligraphy will be seen in the clinics of Chinese medicine practitioners
陳立福の書道が漢方医のクリニックで見られるようになる
Since the period of the Republic of China
中華民国時代から
has always been a supporter of Chinese medicine
私は常に中国医学の支持者であり続けています
But has always been considered a cultural conservative
しかし常に文化的に保守的だと考えられてきた
support based on ideology
イデオロギーに基づいたサポート
support
サポート
But Chen Guofu did
しかし、陳国福はそうしました
led to a scientific experiment in the 1940s
1940年代の科学実験につながった
And this experiment proves the effect of Changshan drug abuse
そしてこの実験は常山の薬物乱用の影響を証明しています
So later this was published in the journal of Science
その後、これはサイエンス誌に掲載されました
At that time, Chang Shan’s article was called
当時、張山の記事はこう呼ばれていました。
Nagayama New Anti-Military Drug
長山New Anti-Military Drug
So it's been proven
それで証明されたんだよ
that result
その結果
Du Congming cited this example in 1929 with only two examples
杜聡明は 1929 年にこの例を 2 つだけ挙げて引用しました。
but he's never been able to do it
しかし彼は一度もそれができなかった
But it proved to be a real success in 1943
しかし、それが本当の成功を収めたのは 1943 年でした。
and what is more important
そしてもっと重要なことは
The results of this research by Gofu
ゴフさんの今回の研究結果
is a study that directly affected last year's Nobel Prize in Qing Hao v.
これは、チン・ハオ対ジョン・ハオの昨年のノーベル賞に直接影響を与えた研究である。
wait until 1967
1967年まで待ってください
As you all know the story we hear now is that
皆さんご存知のとおり、今私たちが聞いている話は次のとおりです。
The CCP used the Vietnam War for the needs of the war
中国共産党は戦争の必要のためにベトナム戦争を利用した
made a political decision
政治的決断を下した
Launch mission 523, right?
ミッション523を打ち上げますよね？
Then began to contribute to the final picture and found Qinghao again
その後、最終的な写真に貢献し始め、再び青海を見つけました
can cause sadism
サディズムを引き起こす可能性がある
And won the Nobel Prize in 2015
そして2015年にはノーベル賞を受賞しました
This is the question we hear most about the history of science in China
これは中国の科学史に関して最もよく聞かれる質問です
It's just that you only hear Chairman Mao's decision
毛沢東の決定だけを聞いているだけだ
But in fact, if we go back and look at his historical materials at that time
しかし実際、当時の史料を遡って見てみると、
at the beginning of this decision
この決定の初めに
The first one in the research on Chinese medicine is Changshan
中国医学の研究の第一弾は常山です
It is because we already know that Changshan is effective
常山が効果的であることはすでにわかっているからです
So there are two consequences
したがって、結果は2つあります
The first is to say
一つ目は言うことです
In the past, people once suspected that Chinese medicine did not abuse people and start addiction again
かつて人々は、漢方薬が人々を虐待して再び依存症を引き起こすことはないのではないかと疑っていました。
How can you find a medicine that works, right?
どうすれば効果のある薬を見つけることができるでしょうか？
Wang Jinwei said so
ワン・ジンウェイはそう言った
He said that I never believe that Chinese medicine can cure infectious diseases
彼は、私は中国医学が感染症を治すことができるとは決して信じていない、と言いました。
But what?
でも何？
In Guofu's experience, we already know that there is indeed
国福の経験では、確かに存在することを私たちはすでに知っています。
Does that make you feel like saying
そう言う気になりますか
probably there will be, right?
おそらくあるでしょうね？
Since they have found an effective drug before
彼らは以前に効果的な薬を発見したので、
Then it's likely they've discovered other medicines
そうすれば、彼らは他の薬を発見した可能性が高い
So the initial research consisted of two parts
したがって、最初の調査は 2 つの部分から構成されていました
One part is hoping to reduce the
一部は削減を期待しています。
That is, serious side effects such as vomiting
つまり、嘔吐などの重篤な副作用が起こるのです。
on the other hand
一方で
Later, if the side effects cannot be reduced, a new drug will be found
その後、副作用を軽減できない場合は、新しい薬が発見されます
Finally found this Qinghaosu
ついにこの青ハオスを見つけました
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
One of the examples selected by Dolceville
ドルチェヴィルが選んだ一例
It's actually a valid example, right?
これは実際に有効な例ですよね?
Moreover, this example directly inspires
さらに、この例は直接的なインスピレーションを与えます
The current one is to say
現在のものは言うことです
The result of such a major scientific research
このような大規模な科学研究の結果
While at the Tuyoyo Drasca Committee
トゥヨヨ・ドラスカ委員会にいる間
committee committee says
委員会委員会は言う
This may be the past 50 years
これは過去50年かもしれない
The development of the most important Syriputics
最も重要なシリピュティクスの開発
he said maybe but
彼はそうかもしれないけど、と言いました
as you can imagine
あなたが想像できるように
this is a very
これはとても
This is a
これは
Just look at this situation
この状況を見てください
What about this period of history?
この時代の歴史はどうでしょうか？
And what?
そして何？
And not only is Du Congming right
杜聡明が正しいだけではない
That's right, the medicine
そうです、薬です
And in fact Chen Guofu
そして実際、陳国福
Only the process of finding this medicine
この薬を見つけるまでの過程だけ
It is very similar to what Du Congming said
杜聡明の言ったこととよく似ています
I wrote a long article on this
これについて長い記事を書きました
It's almost a joke
それはほとんど冗談です
As far as Chen Guofu's original and most primitive way is to
陳国福のオリジナルで最も原始的な方法は次のとおりです。
He took a visitor to his house
彼は訪問者を自分の家に連れて行った
He just feeds him
彼はただ彼に餌を与えるだけです
That's the man who got sadism
あれはサディズムに陥った男だ
He was cured later, he was very happy
その後治ってとても幸せそうでした
Then he was at the Central Political School in Chongqing
その後、彼は重慶の中央政治学校に通っていました。
It is the National Chengchi University in Taiwan today.
現在の台湾の国立政治大学です。
He is still the provost
彼は今でも知事だ
He taught them the people in the discipline
彼は人々に規律を教えた
put them bdsm students
彼らをBDSM学生に置きます
Take this medicine for them all
全員にこの薬を飲ませてください
Then it turns out the saddle bugs in their middle school are really down
その後、彼らの中学校のサドルバグが本当に減ったことが判明しました
He just set up a laboratory
彼は研究室を設立したばかりです
so it's really a
だからそれは本当に
Experimental research on humans first
まずは人体での実験研究
and therefore later
したがって、後で
Other guests criticize him when they come to see it
他の客がそれを見に来ると彼を批判する
That is to say, he is the life of Chaojian
つまり、彼はチャオジャンの命​​です。
And what?
そして何？
That is, this is actually a medical waste
つまり、これは実際には医療廃棄物です
So he was criticized a lot
それで彼はかなり批判された
he can't refute
彼は反論できない
He only said that others criticized me as 54321
彼は、他の人が私を54321と批判したとだけ言いました。
I am the pervert
私は変態です
he can't refute
彼は反論できない
But not only
しかしそれだけではありません
Chen Guofu's successful case
陳国福の成功例
It is parallel to what Du Congming said
それは杜聡明の言ったことと同じだ
there is one more important thing
もう一つ重要なことがある
Let me tell you about this process in detail
このプロセスについて詳しく説明します
that is
あれは
The first step in 54321 is chemical analysis
54321 の最初のステップは化学分析です
but many people will say
しかし多くの人はこう言うだろう
To go further, you have to figure out first
さらに先に進むには、まず次のことを理解する必要があります
You should analyze which crude drug, right?
どの生薬を分析する必要がありますか？
So you're doing pharmacognosy research
薬理学の研究をしているんですね
know what is this long mountain
この長い山が何なのか知っていますか
so in other words
つまり、言い換えれば
Not just 12345 should be 012345
12345 だけではなく 012345 にする必要があります
You first know what Changshan is
常山が何であるかを初めて知ります
to find the components
コンポーネントを見つけるには
for animal experiments
動物実験を行う
But what?
でも何？
In Guofu's case?
郭福の場合は？
he didn't
彼はしませんでした
i just told you
私はちょうどあなたに言いました
He went directly to the local
彼は直接現地へ行った
From today's pharmacy to buy medicine
今日の薬局から薬を買うまで
Is it for the receptionist?
受付嬢用でしょうか？
Wait until it proves effective
効果が出るまで待つ
Re-establish a research laboratory
再成立研究室
Then find everyone to make herbal medicine
それからみんなで漢方薬を作ってください
Chemistry Clinical Aspects of Research
化学研究の臨床的側面
Just wait until it's time to do research in reverse
逆に研究する時が来るまで待ってください
A surprising thing was found to be
驚くべきことが分かりました
Suppose they start
彼らが始めたとします
If you do pharmacognosy research first
まず薬理研究を行う場合
what's your first step
あなたの最初の一歩は何ですか
That's what Du Congming said
杜聡明はこう言った
Because Japan has the greatest contribution
日本は最大の貢献をしているから
We're looking at Japanese scientific literature research
ここでは日本の科学文献研究を調べています
right
右
that japan as early as
あの日本は早くも
Japan is already here
日本はもうここにある
In 1827, the plant of this long mountain was found
1827年にこの長い山の植物が発見されました
The identity of the plant
植物の正体
in 1827
1827年に
This youth achievement has been found
この若者の成果が見つかりました
And since then, it has been followed and everyone believes
それ以来、それが守られ、誰もが信じています
Most of the scientists in the Republic of China
中華民国のほとんどの科学者は、
also follow this noun
この名詞にも続きます
It is believed that the plants of Nagayama originated from this
永山の植物はここから生まれたと考えられています。
But because their research on Guofu this time is to do clinical work first.
しかし、今回のGuofuの研究は、まず臨床作業を行うためです。
So they later found out that
それで、彼らは後でそれを知りました
the long mountain that really works
本当に機能する長い山
Oh, that is to say, the Japanese have already found out about this research
ああ、つまり日本人はすでにこの研究のことを知っているということだ
But said he couldn't cure sadism
しかし彼はサディズムを治すことはできないと言った
That's because Guofu's story was done clinically first.
それは、国府の話が臨床的に先に行われたものだからです。
Already know it works, right?
それが機能することはすでに知っていますよね?
So later found out that
それで後で知ったのですが、
It turns out that we are not using this medicine, not this plant
私たちが使用しているのはこの薬ではなく、この植物ではないことが判明しました
It's another ancient mountain
これもまた古代の山です
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
It's because you didn't use one two three four five
ワン・ツー・スリー・フォー・ファイブを使わなかったからだよ
So you know this knowledge is wrong
つまり、この知識が間違っていることはわかります
Do you understand what I mean?
私の言っている意味が分かりますか？
So it was very scientific from the beginning
つまり最初から非常に科学的でした
First come to the scientists and then check the
まず科学者のところに来て、それから、
latest scientific literature
最新の科学文献
Otherwise, he couldn't find this long mountain
そうでなければ、彼はこの長い山を見つけることができなかったでしょう
Because this Changshan is mainly produced in Japan and South Korea
この常山は主に日本と韓国で生産されているため、
Otherwise, he really bought this Changshan
そうでなければ、彼は本当にこの常山を買ったのです
Then use it to prove the conclusion of the Japanese
次に、それを使って日本人の結論を証明します。
There's just no cure for sadism
サディズムを治す方法はない
But because he immediately went straight to the local pharmacy to buy
しかし、彼はすぐに近所の薬局に買いに行ったので、
pharmacy bought medicine
薬局で薬を買った
So it can be seen from this
ということで、このことからもわかります
The local pharmacy knows what works, right?
地元の薬局なら何が効くか知っていますよね？
And because he bought that medicine first
そして、彼が最初にその薬を買ったので、
Conversely know it works
逆に、それが機能することを知ってください
I found it wasn't this plant
この植物ではないことがわかりました
So he came to the conclusion that
そこで彼は次のような結論に達しました
The Japanese keep getting it wrong
日本人はいつも誤解している
The Japanese say Hechangshan
日本人は和昌山と言う
It is different from Changshan in China
中国の常山とは違う
That's the history we just had
それが私たちが経験したばかりの歴史です
Materia Medica Research in Japan
日本進行本草研究
It is because some plants do not grow in Japan
日本では育たない植物もあるから
He looks for alternative plants
彼は代替植物を探しています
But I'm not going far now
でも今は遠くへは行かない
just say a little bit
少しだけ言ってください
In this case
この場合
This successful example is not only
この成功例はそれだけではありません
not one two three four five
1 2 3 4 5 ではありません
And we can conversely say
そして逆に言うこともできます
It's because he's not one, two, three, four, five that he succeeds so quickly
彼がこれほど早く成功するのは、彼が 1、2、3、4、5 ではないからだ
right
右
Otherwise, it would not be easy to succeed so quickly
そうでなければ、これほど早く成功するのは簡単ではないでしょう
so this is
それでこれは
Another interesting point in this case
この場合のもう一つの興味深い点
So the story is actually more like
したがって、ストーリーは実際には次のようなものです
Clinical application comes to a historical process of pharmacognosy research
臨床応用は薬理研究の歴史的な過程を経て生まれる
ok so what?
わかりました、それで何ですか？
Du Congming said lightly
杜聡明は軽く言った。
this is also a good way
これも良い方法です
But in the period of the Republic of China to adopt this idea
しかし、中華民国の時代にこの考えが採用されるようになりました。
Everyone is scolded to death
みんな死ぬほど叱られる
can't defend myself
自分を守ることができない
Like this doctor of traditional Chinese medicine, he said
この中医学の医師のように、彼はこう言いました。
Regardless of any drug, first determine its principle from science
どんな薬であっても、まずは科学から原理を解明する
clinically validated
臨床的に検証された
The truth is very smooth, but it is difficult to fake it
真実はとても滑らかだが、それを偽造するのは難しい
Know from clinical knowledge first, then go to principle from scientific verification
まずは臨床的に知り、科学的検証から原理へ
Prepare for troubles
トラブルに備える
That's a defense he barely makes
それは彼がかろうじて行う防御だ
But it's weak to say it, right?
でもそれを言うのは弱いですよね？
So you can see that
それでわかります
The results are attached here
結果はここに添付されています
in the plain looking lexeme
単純な語彙素で
He proposes a potentially highly controversial
彼は潜在的に非常に物議を醸す可能性のある提案をしている
And it is not accepted by others
そしてそれは他人には受け入れられない
He has
彼は持っています
He is in a research project
彼は研究プロジェクトに参加しています
To introduce a new discipline
新しい学問を導入するには
create a new institution
新しい機関を創設する
make another
別のものを作る
a new research method
新しい研究方法
There are just too many anomalies that challenge the original research paradigm
本来の研究パラダイムに挑戦する異常が多すぎる
It's no wonder that you will be criticized by others
他人から批判されても不思議ではない
OK, so I'll put it in five veins now
OK、それでは 5 つの静脈に入れます
let's come back
戻りましょう
It turns out that I was talking about the mystery of Du Congming's research
どうやら私は杜崇明の研究の謎について話していたようです
We can get an idea of ​​what
私たちは何についてのアイデアを得ることができますか
That's why he continued his life promoting unscientific
だからこそ彼は非科学的なことを宣伝する人生を続けたのだ
What about research methods that are considered unscientific?
非科学的とみなされる研究方法についてはどうですか?
From our point of view today
今日の私たちの視点から
It doesn't seem like he's promoting some unscientific research method
非科学的な研究方法を推進しているわけではないようです
Instead, a research approach with multiple breakthroughs
代わりに、複数のブレークスルーを伴う研究アプローチ
right
右
That means his research was indeed influenced by Japan
ということは、彼の研究は確かに日本の影響を受けていたということになる
Inspired by Japanese Pharmacy
日本の薬局からインスピレーションを得た
but he introduced experimental therapeutics
しかし彼は実験的な治療法を導入しました
To break through the tradition of no therapeutic research in the Japanese Empire at that time
当時の大日本帝国では治療研究が行われていなかったという伝統を打破するために
And it also broke through in the West
そして西洋でもブレイクしました
You have no tradition of using experimental therapeutics to study herbal medicine
あなたには漢方薬を研究するために実験的治療法を使用する伝統がありません
Both are breakthroughs
どちらも画期的です
Then you turned to the context of the Republic of China and spoke
それからあなたは中華民国の文脈に目を向けて話しました。
He is a tall man that is to say
つまり彼は背が高い男だ
best scientific training but he chooses to do research like this
最高の科学的トレーニングだが、彼はこのような研究をすることを選んだ
Then he will introduce an East Asian
それから彼は東アジア人を紹介します
Unheard of idea for a research hospital
研究病院のための前代未聞のアイデア
Then came a highly controversial one
その後、非常に物議を醸したものが登場しました
The Way of Doing the Right Way
その逆の研究方法
And this research method was later proven to be effective, right?
そして、この研究方法は後に有効であることが証明されましたよね？
So from this point of view, even if there is no why puzzle
したがって、この観点から、たとえなぜパズルが存在しなかったとしても、
There is no way to untie it, I think at least everyone can
それを解く方法はありません、少なくとも誰でもできると思います
One thing I feel is that he's definitely not an understatement when he mentions this whole project.
私が感じるのは、彼がこのプロジェクト全体について言及するとき、決して過小評価ではないということです。
or the traditional way
または伝統的な方法
but a very forward looking
しかし、とても前向きです
That is to say, a breakthrough idea
つまり画期的なアイデア
I hope everyone can feel that this can be established
これは成立するということを皆さんにも感じていただければと思います
That
それか
And I can't help but want to say one more thing
そしてもう一つ言いたくて仕方がありません
maybe not directly related to puzzle solving
謎解きとは直接関係ないかもしれない
That said, I think it's not only a pretty groundbreaking idea
とはいえ、これは単に画期的なアイデアというだけではないと思います
It's actually a very strategic and ambitious idea
これは実際には非常に戦略的で野心的なアイデアです
Because in many ways
なぜなら、いろんな意味で
He was on the edge, right?
彼は危機に瀕していましたね？
In terms of modern medicine
現代医学的に言えば
He didn't have experimental therapeutics in Imperial Japan
彼は大日本帝国では実験的な治療法を持っていませんでした
compared to imperial japan
大日本帝国と比べて
Of course Taiwan is not a center of medicine
もちろん台湾は医療の中心地ではありません
Compared with traditional Chinese or traditional Chinese words
伝統的な中国や中国医学の言葉と比較してください
Of course also the center
もちろんセンターも
We will take it for granted that it is right in China
中国ではそれが正しいことだと私たちは考えるでしょう
But he doesn't limit himself by fear of the edge
しかし、彼は限界を恐れて自分自身を制限することはありません
Instead he combines all the edges together
代わりに、すべてのエッジを結合します
and became a very groundbreaking idea
非常に画期的なアイデアとなりました
So after he combined these edge positions where they were originally located,
したがって、これらのエッジ位置を元の位置に結合した後、
He can use the rigorous training and qualifications of scientists rarely seen in the Republic of China
彼は中華民国ではめったに見られない科学者の厳しい訓練と資格を活用することができる
is the qualification
資格です
Experimental Therapeutics was developed even after the Japanese Empire was established in Taiwan
台湾で大日本帝国が成立した後も実験療法は発展した
Building and researching traditional medicine in East Asia that the Western world has not fully mastered
西洋世界が完全には習得していない東アジアの伝統医学を構築し、研究する
So if this thing is really done for him
それで、これが本当に彼のために行われたのなら
He does have a unique trait, doesn't he?
彼は独特の特徴を持っていますね。
Hardly anyone is his main competitor
彼の主な競争相手はほとんどいない
I think it's a very ambitious
とても野心的なことだと思います
And I am very active in the idea of ​​combining my weaknesses into strengths
そして、私は自分の弱点を強みに組み合わせるというアイデアに非常に積極的です
at least to me
少なくとも私にとっては
It's very inspiring, so I want to share it with you.
とても感動的な内容なので、皆さんにもシェアしたいと思います。
Well
良い
If we start from this point of view
この観点から始めると
We can have a few further questions
さらにいくつか質問があります
One is why Du Congming has the value of traditional medicine
一つは、杜聡明が伝統医学としての価値を持つ理由です。
have such deep appreciation
とても深い感謝を持っています
to conceive of such a groundbreaking research project
このような画期的な研究プロジェクトを思いつくには
Because everyone can feel it
誰もが感じられるから
The reason why he wants to come up with so many breakthroughs
彼がこれほど多くのブレークスルーを考え出す理由
There is a big reason
大きな理由があります
He believes in the value of traditional medicine more than
彼は伝統医学の価値を何よりも信じています。
The value of our research with pharmaceutical methods
製薬学的手法を用いた研究の価値
right
右
He understands that
彼はそれを理解しています
so what
だから何
Because he believes that there is such a value that far exceeds the current realization
今の現実をはるかに超えた価値があると信じているから
He's the one who conceived of a breakthrough research project.
彼は画期的な研究プロジェクトを発案した人です。
Why does he have such deep appreciation
なぜ彼はこれほど深い感謝の念を抱いているのか
that's actually a good question
それは本当に良い質問です
And this also involves the history of Chinese medicine in Taiwan
そして、これには台湾の中医学の歴史も関係しています。
But I can't tell you now
でも今は言えない
back back give complete answer
戻って戻って完全な答えを与える
but i think it's an interesting question
しかし、それは興味深い質問だと思います
what about the second one
2番目はどうですか
Everyone like just now if it sounds like after
後みたいに聞こえるならみんな今が好き
should feel a little bit
少しは感じるはずだ
I think Du Congming now sounds
杜聡明は今だと思う
Du Congming is a very normal scientist
杜聡明はごく普通の科学者です
normal but ambitious scientist
普通だが野心的な科学者
It's just a normal research project, right?
それは普通の研究プロジェクトですよね？
Then where is my Du cleverness fascinated?
では、私のドゥの賢さはどこに惹かれるのでしょうか？
If everyone now thinks that I seem to cancel Du Congming to be fascinated
私が杜聡明への執着を解消しようとしているように見えると皆が思っているなら
That is to say, our second question is to say
つまり、2 番目の質問は次のとおりです。
Why such a breakthrough research project
なぜこのような画期的な研究プロジェクトが行われるのか
still persists as a conservative
今も保守派として根強く残っている
Conservative and reactionary approach
保守的かつ反動的なアプローチ
Then I will now return to the main axis of our article
それでは記事の主軸に戻ります
This is largely the same as what we just said
これは先ほど述べたこととほぼ同じです
the Great Rupture of Modernity
近代性の大断絶
That's why the so-called Du is clever and fascinated
だからこそ、いわゆるドゥは賢くて魅力的です
In fact, it has nothing to do with Du Congming
実は杜聡明とは何の関係もありません
he is a normal scientist
彼は普通の科学者です
Just might suggest some more cutting edge
より最先端のものを提案するかもしれません
more challenging
より挑戦的な
existing scientific research methods
既存の科学研究手法
So let's put it
それでは、それを置きましょう
If we think he's a fan
彼がファンだと思うなら
words that can't even be played
再生すらできない言葉
just reflects people's static view of science
科学に対する人々の静的な見方を反映しているだけです
especially regarding modern science and traditional medicine as two opposing
特に現代科学と伝統医学を相反するものとして考える
holistic view of science
科学の全体的な見方
This is the atmosphere of the whole era
これが時代全体の雰囲気です
even to some extent today
今日でもある程度は
are still the atmosphere of our time
まだ私たちの時代の雰囲気が残っています
If I am wrong, please correct me, Vice President Liu.
もし私が間違っていたら、訂正してください、劉副大統領。
I heard
私は聞いた
I remember that academicians of Academia Sinica discussed it ten years ago
10年前に中央研究院の学者たちがそれについて議論したことを覚えています
Should Chinese medicine or Chinese medicine be an elective course in medical school?
中医学または漢方医学は医学部の選択科目にすべきでしょうか？
It seems that the academicians object
学者たちは反対しているようだ
Said that because the Taiwanese are superstitious enough
台湾人は迷信深いからそう言った
If the Academia Sinica takes the lead in incorporating this course into the teaching materials of the medical school
中央研究院が率先してこの講座を医学部の教材に取り入れたら
Taiwanese will become more superstitious
台湾人は迷信深くなるだろう
It's a sign that a problem is still alive
それは問題がまだ生きていることの兆候です
right
右
That is to say, if today we cannot clearly distinguish
つまり、今日私たちが明確に区別できない場合、
What is science, what is not science, what is tradition, what is modern
科学とは何か、科学ではないもの、伝統とは何か、現代とは何か
if you don't know
知らないなら
Then everything has to be examined and debated one by one.
次に、すべてを一つ一つ検討し、議論する必要があります。
This political Du Congyuan first said what he didn't want to do
この政治家の杜従源は、最初に自分のやりたくないことを言った
It's something the Fusni man said he wouldn't do.
それはファスニ人がやらないと言っていたことだ。
He said it was very clear, right?
彼はそれが非常に明確だと言いましたよね？
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
Our Great Rupture in Modernity
近代における大きな断絶
If it can be established
それが確立できれば
must be very clear
非常に明確でなければなりません
Who is scientific progress and who is conservative and reactionary
誰が科学の進歩で、誰が保守的で反動的なのか
right
右
that way you can make a lot of decisions without doubt
そうすれば、疑いなく多くの決定を下すことができます
don't say anything, you start to feel like saying
何も言わないで、言いたくなってきた
This matter is not good for our situation in Taiwan.
この問題は台湾の状況にとって好ましくありません。
different from anywhere in the world
世界中のどことも違う
then everything needs to be discussed
それならすべてを話し合う必要がある
So under this big break in modernity?
では、この近代化の大きな変化の下で？
It's hard for you to tolerate thoughts like Du Congming's
杜聡明のような考えを容認するのは難しい
in his thoughts
彼の考えの中で
He is not only a representative of modernity
彼は現代性の代表者であるだけではありません
and he feels
そして彼は感じます
The value that exists in the tradition is worth learning
伝統の価値は学ぶ価値がある
far beyond what we understand today
今日私たちが理解していることをはるかに超えています
so that we are worth developing
私たちが成長する価値があるように
Some newer research methods
いくつかの新しい研究方法
Even challenge the existing research methods
既存の研究手法にも挑戦する
to realize these values
これらの価値観を実現するために
That's exactly what it means
まさにそういう意味です
in those days or today
あの頃も今も
Many times we are not able to
できないことが多い
accepted things
受け入れられたもの
That
それか
It is precisely because of the fact that Du Congming was included in the modernity discourse
それはまさに杜聡明が近代性の言説に含まれていたからである。
And one of the poles of our common sense
そして私たちの常識の極の一つ
Therefore, Du Congming's research on Chinese Yi medicine
したがって、杜崇明の中国李医学の研究は、
had to become a
にならなければならなかった
The mystery of unknown language
未知の言語の謎
So I don't know if people will think that it means
だから人々がそれが意味すると思うかどうかはわかりません
We heard on the one hand that he had three studies
一方では、彼は3つの研究をしていたということを聞きました
But now if you go to see
でも今見に行ったら
There are so many books about Du Congming
杜聡明に関する本はたくさんあります
Almost none of us have heard of the research on Chinese Yi medicine
中国の易医学の研究について聞いたことがある人はほとんどいません。
right
右
Even if everyone mentions
みんなが言及しても
It's a bit embarrassing
ちょっと恥ずかしいです
And then and historically he has never been able to
そして歴史的に彼は決してそれができなかった
put it into practice
それを実践する
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
This is such a very creative project
これはとてもクリエイティブなプロジェクトです
It became impossible to realize back then
あの頃は実感できなくなった
And this year we have no way to incorporate the easy
そして今年は、簡単な方法を取り入れる方法がありません。
He made a Taiwan medical modernity
彼は台湾の医療を近代化した
or the image of the representative of scientific modernity
または科学的近代性の代表者のイメージ
Putting it into this story seems to create a
それをこの物語に組み込むと、
figuratively
比喩的に
Maybe some people will think it's a stain
汚れだと思う人もいるかもしれない
That is to say, because of this, it becomes impossible for us to see this
つまり、このせいで私たちにはこれを見ることができなくなります。
see him like this
こんな彼を見て
Well, now I'm at the end of my speech.
さて、これで私のスピーチは終わりです。
I just started talking to you about a big issue that concerns me, right?
私が懸念している大きな問題についてあなたに話し始めたところですよね？
That is to say, how has Chinese medicine developed within half a century
つまり、半世紀の間に中医学はどのように発展してきたのかということです。
From 1925 to 1997
1925 年から 1997 年まで
From the deadly enemy of modernity to the most concrete symbol and tool of Chinese exploration and modernity
近代性の致命的な敵から、中国の探検と近代性の最も具体的なシンボルとツールまで
Then the example I gave you today is not an example in the context of China
それでは、私が今日挙げた例は中国の例ではありません。
But an example of a parallel correlation
しかし、並列相関の例としては、
And then I by this case
そして私はこの件で
That said, let's say this is my main title
とはいえ、これが私のメインタイトルだとしましょう
If we try to put the story of Du Congming into this historical transformation
杜崇明の物語をこの歴史的変遷に当てはめてみると
what would we think
私たちはどう思いますか
I think everyone would sometimes think about why this transformation happened.
なぜこのような変化が起こったのか、誰もが時々考えることがあると思います。
The easiest thing to think of is how many
一番考えやすいのは、何個かということです
One is that China is very backward anyway, right?
1つは、中国はとにかく非常に後進的だということですよね？
So there has been no progress
だから何の進展もなかった
Even the original research results of the academic circles would think that
学界の独自の研究結果でもこう考えられるでしょう。
used by Mao Zedong
毛沢東が使った
to claim a new China with a very different science
まったく異なる科学で新しい中国を主張する
So support TCM for political reasons
政治的理由から中医学を支持する
This is for academia
これは学術向けです
before i wrote my book
本を書く前に
This is the most popular saying
これは最も有名な格言です
That is to say, to explain this process of historical transformation in this way
つまり、この歴史的変革の過程をこのように説明するのです。
But if we now
でも今なら
Putting this historical course in the words of a smart story
この歴史的経過をスマートな物語の言葉で表現する
we added a lot
私たちはたくさん追加しました
such a parallel story
そんなパラレルな話
In such traditional thinking
このような伝統的な考え方では
elements that cannot be seen
見えない要素
For example, the Japanese medicinal tradition
たとえば、日本の伝統医学
right
右
that is
あれは
The process of historical transformation
歴史的変革の過程
It is related to the scientific development of Japan
それは日本の科学の発展に関係しています
This is not a story that happened entirely in China
これは完全に中国で起こった話ではない
and in fact in my book
そして実際に私の本の中で
There are also references to more Japanese influences
より多くの日本の影響についての言及もあります
For example, in the late Qing Dynasty
たとえば、清朝末期には
After all, it was already very bad.
結局のところ、それはすでに非常に悪かったです。
Later, it was because Japan still kept the truth
その後、日本が真実を隠し続けたからだ
That's why the reformers of Chinese medicine in the Republic of China said
だからこそ、中華民国の中国医学の改革者たちはこう言ったのです。
We should pull the truth back to the core of Chinese medicine
真実を中医学の核心に戻さなければなりません
become one of his four main axes
彼の4つの主軸の1つになる
That's why it's 1971
だから1971年なんだよ
That is to say, Restin went to China to discover the real situation
つまり、レスティンは実態を知るために中国へ行ったのです
So there are scientific implications in this story
したがって、この話には科学的な意味合いがあります
Also has Japanese influence
也有日本的影響
Second Experimental Therapeutics
第二の実験的治療法
this story is not a
この物語はそうではありません
It is a historical process with many new scientific developments
これは多くの新しい科学的発展を伴う歴史的なプロセスです
So people who try to support Chinese medicine
ですから、中国医学をサポートしようとする人々は、
Not all conservative and reactionary people
保守的で反動的な人々がすべてではない
Instead, many of them want to bring in the latest
その代わりに、彼らの多くは最新のものを導入したいと考えています。
Introduce and seriously attempt to introduce the latest scientific developments
最新の科学的発展を紹介し、真剣に導入しようとする
Come into this history and give him evidence
この歴史に立ち入って証拠をあげてください
The third is that they don't even just import
3つ目は、単に輸入するだけではないということです。
even in their environment
彼らの環境でも
Attempt to create a unique local research method
独自の地域調査手法の創出に挑戦
Of course, this will meet with great resistance.
もちろん、これには大きな抵抗が生じるでしょう。
Just like Du Congming's "Tao Xing Reverse Casting"
杜聡明の「陶興逆鋳造」みたいに
What about the fourth?
4番目はどうでしょうか？
That is to say, the person concerned does have a value for traditional medical treatment.
つまり、当事者は伝統的な医療に価値を持っているのです。
is a very deep understanding
とても深い理解です
Moreover, Du Congming mentioned Changshan
さらに杜聡明は常山について言及した。
this specific drug
この特定の薬
What everyone wants to see is actually really surprising, right?
みんなが見たいものって、実はすごく意外ですよね？
He only lifted two pills and he lifted one
彼は錠剤を 2 錠しか持ち上げず、そのうちの 1 錠を持ち上げた
Drugs that were later proven to be effective
後に効果が証明された薬
And this Changshan, although in Du Congming's story
そしてこの常山ですが、杜崇明の物語の中では
He has been unable to bring this research to fruition
彼はこの研究を実現させることができなかった
Only one ideal is missing
理想がひとつだけ足りない
And not only there is no way to realize it, but only an ideal
そしてそれを実現する方法がないだけでなく、理想があるだけです
and in our history
そして私たちの歴史の中で
We hardly even know about it
私たちはそれについてほとんど知りません
But he's in another vein
しかし、彼は別の方向にいます
parallel unrelated
平行無関係
Chen Guofu has not read Du Congming's article
陳国福は杜聡明の記事を読んでいない
as far as i know no
私の知る限りではありません
But after 1945, he had contacted Du Congming
しかし、1945 年以降、彼は杜聡明に連絡を取った。
But the development of Changshan is independent of Du Congming
しかし、常山の発展は杜聡明とは独立したものである。
this suggested
これは示唆しました
It has been proven that it can indeed treat malaria
実際にマラリアを治療できることが証明されている
and even contributed to a
そして、
major breakthrough in medicine
医学における大きな進歩
Qinghaosu
チンハオス
so i now
だから私は今
last say
最後に言う
I can't give you a story about this
これについてはお話できません
complete conclusion
完全な結論
But if you take this story
しかし、この話を取り上げると、
put it in
入れたら
We feel this transformation process
この変化の過程を私たちは感じます
Shouldn't just be entirely traditional
完全に伝統的なものであってはなりません
right
右
It is not because Chinese medicine has always maintained a traditional situation
それは中医学が常に伝統的な状況を維持しているからではありません
And after this transformation
そしてこの変身後は
On the contrary, he follows the trend of the modern system
それどころか、彼は現代のシステムの流れに従っています
There is a lot of interaction
交流がたくさんあります
And what?
そして何？
But what about this history?
しかし、この歴史はどうでしょうか？
also full of creativity
クリエイティビティにも溢れている
There are many people who think
と思っている人も多いのではないでしょうか
They know the value of traditional medicine
彼らは伝統医学の価値を知っています
come up with creative ways
創造的な方法を考え出す
hope to confirm
確認したい
In his example there is no way to achieve
彼の例では、それを達成する方法はありません
But here it is implemented
しかし、ここではそれが実装されています
Du Congming
杜聡明
And it's important to
そして重要なことは、
such historical cases
このような歴史的な事例
most of our time
私たちのほとんどの時間
When we think about this history
この歴史を考えると
almost completely invisible
ほぼ完全に見えない
without entering our consciousness
私たちの意識に入ることなく
So the last thing I want to tell you is
それで最後に言いたいのは、
The development of this history
この歴史の発展
maybe more than we thought
おそらく私たちが思っていた以上に
a lot more interesting
もっと面白い
And it is worth our deep thinking
そしてそれは私たちが深く考える価値があります
that ends my report
これで私のレポートは終わりです
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thank you very much Dr. Lei for a very wonderful presentation
レイ博士、素晴らしいプレゼンテーションをありがとうございました
shall we be more open
もっとオープンにしましょうか
Is there anything I want to ask Dr. Lei?
レイ博士に聞きたいことはありますか?
Or some comments are welcome
またはコメントも歓迎です
Hello, teacher
こんにちは先生
When I was in 2006
私が2006年の頃
Graduated from National Taiwan University School of Medicine
国立台湾大学医学部卒業
for new drug development
新薬開発のために
So about what you said ten years ago
それで、10年前にあなたが言ったことについて
Academician of Central Plains
セントラルプレーンズの学者
Then they opposed Chinese medicine research
その後彼らは中国医学の研究に反対した
I remember this incident very clearly
この出来事はとても鮮明に覚えています
Because in fact, even National Taiwan University Hospital
実際、国立台湾大学病院でも
They probably lasted until 100 years
おそらく100年まで続いたでしょう
In the 100th year of the Republic of China
中華民国100周年に
Only then did they really feel that doing Chinese medicine research
そのとき初めて、彼らは中国医学の研究をすることが本当に重要だと実感しました。
is valuable
貴重です
Before that in National Taiwan University Hospital
その前に国立台湾大学病院にて
You said you want to do Chinese medicine
漢方やりたいって言ってたね
people will think
人々は考えるだろう
think you are weird
あなたは変だと思う
right
右
so this thing is true
だからこれは本当だ
And about the perverse
そして変態について
It is Mr. Du Congming's perverse research method
杜聡明氏のひねくれた研究法です
So I knew it when I was in the National Taiwan University Hospital
国立台湾大学病院にいたとき、私はそれを知りました。
And then when I started doing medicine
そして私が薬を飲み始めたとき
At that time, Omics in the world was physical science
当時、世界ではオミクスは物理科学でした
Right technology started to develop
適切なテクノロジーが開発され始めた
Then don't say that you will be criticized at that time
じゃあその時批判されるとか言わないでね
When we were making medicine
薬を作っていた頃
what we are happy about is
私たちが幸せなことは
In the bamboo, you can buy the general clothes
竹では一般的な衣類を購入できます
Zhipuyi is theoretically a kind of
Zhipuyi は理論的には次のようなものです。
what do you put in
何を入れますか
Then all his ingredients will be beaten out of the one
そうすれば、彼の材料はすべて一つから打ち出されるでしょう
We are very happy to ask the senior
先輩方に聞いていただけると嬉しいです
Hey, senior, why does the teacher only look at one component at a time?
ねえ、先輩、なぜ先生は一度に 1 つのコンポーネントしか見ないのですか?
why didn't he say
なぜ彼は言わなかったのですか
Pull out everything in the tape sample you analyzed
分析したテープサンプルのすべてを引き出します
Why would you take that Profi
なぜそのプロフィを取るのですか
just as long as it's not this
それがそうでない限り
Delete all the medicines we want to see
確認したい薬をすべて削除します
But there might be something else very important in him
しかし、彼の中には何か他の非常に重要なものがあるかもしれません
For example, it doesn't matter if he wears something
たとえば、彼が何かを着ているかどうかは関係ありません
Then I was scolded by the senior
そしたら先輩に怒られました
He said don't ask strange questions
彼は変な質問をするなと言った
You get punched every time you ask weird questions
変な質問するたびに殴られるよ
So I used to be scolded by the teacher
それでこの前先生に怒られたんです
And then later when I left the State Department
そしてその後私が国務省を去ったとき
Then when I went to the hospital to do clinical work
それから私が臨床業務を行うために病院に行ったとき
I found out that it's not just the teacher who scolds you
あなたを叱るのは先生だけではないことが分かりました
The teacher is more kind
先生はもっと優しいです
you are IRB
あなたは治験審査委員会です
When the human experimentation committee held the cannon accountable
人体実験委員会が大砲の責任を追及したとき
that's the scariest thing
それが一番怖いことだ
but i think in fact
でも実際はそう思う
we should be able to say
私たちは言えるはずです
The teachers of the Human Clinical Trials Committee
ヒト臨床試験委員会の先生方
he doesn't seem to understand
彼は理解していないようだ
Is it the value of this matter?
それはこの問題の価値ですか？
So what you said, teacher
それで、先生、何と言ったんですか？
In fact, until now
実は今まで
I think he is still in Taiwan
彼はまだ台湾にいると思います
keeps happening
起こり続ける
yes then that about
はい、それではそのことについて
that traditional medicine
その伝統医学
Why is he fighting for this technology
なぜ彼はこのテクノロジーのために戦っているのか
i remember i was in 2011
2011年だったことを覚えています
When studying Chinese medicine at Yangming University
陽明大学で中医学を学ぶとき
At that time, I was also very happy to learn to fight for
あの時、私も戦うことを学べてとても嬉しかったです。
But everyone says I don't have wisdom roots
でもみんなは私には知恵の根がないって言う
Because it is not only people who can fight
戦えるのは人だけじゃないから
you may find it difficult for you to study
あなたは勉強するのが難しいと感じるかもしれません
But not only people can fight
しかし、戦えるのは人間だけではない
You can fight for the teacher
先生のために戦えるよ
But then this problem will come
しかし、その後、この問題が発生します
you're going to poke a mouse
あなたはマウスをつつくつもりですか
how do you know
どうして知っていますか
What position did you poke at?
どの位置で突いたの？
We poke down every time
私たちは毎回突き落とします
See when the muscles shake
筋肉が震える瞬間を観察する
we just want that right
私たちはただそれが正しいことを望んでいます
But you can't poke someone like this
でもこんな風に人を刺すことはできない
right
右
So at that time there was a senior doctor of traditional Chinese medicine
それで当時、中医学の上級医師がいました。
just teach me how to feel the pulse
脈拍の感じ方を教えてください
they will say why
彼らは理由を言うだろう
I can't tell the difference
違いが分かりません
Pregnant women's pulse will be slippery
妊婦の脈は滑りやすくなる
But I'm going to take the boy's pulse
でも、私はその少年の脈を測るつもりです
Then
それから
Then there was one time in that
それから、ある時がありました
The Department of Health has organized the Chinese Medicine Research Conference
保健省は中国医学研究カンファレンスを主催しました
I was
私はそうでした
I talked about this with teachers from other countries
このことについて他の国の先生たちと話しました
I say it's very disturbing
とても不安だと言います
I am really good at saving the world
私は世界を救うのが本当に得意です
And foreign scholars like it very much
外国の学者もそれをとても気に入っています
But is there any way
しかし、何か方法はありますか
Do quantitative methods to help everyone
全員を助けるために定量的な方法を実行する
Interpretation
解釈
Then until about 2014
それから2014年くらいまで
American MIT
アメリカのMIT
They are really scholars
彼らは本当に学者です
They published a study called
彼らは、と呼ばれる研究を発表しました。
action
動作
microscope
顕微鏡
is that it can be more than just
それは単なるものではないということです
the lips
唇
or
また
pulse
脈
it can help you zoom in
ズームインするのに役立ちます
So you can clearly judge
はっきりと判断できるので、
is this a patient
これは患者ですか
is it healthy or sick
健康ですか、それとも病気ですか
or it lips what it's talking about
またはそれが話していることを口で言う
Yes, and with this technology
はい、そしてこのテクノロジーを使用すると、
then actually
それから実際に
You can actually apply it to
実際に応用できるのは、
The pulse condition of traditional Chinese medicine is interpreted
漢方の脈状態を読み解く
Right and so this is Chinese medicine
そうです、これが漢方薬です
Why is it now the subject of Zhengjiu technology?
なぜ今、Zhengjiu テクノロジーの話題になっているのでしょうか?
It is now de facto important in East Asia
それは今や東アジアにおいて事実上重要です
a door
一門
precious
貴重
The reason people will call it a real treasure
本物の宝物と呼ばれる理由
And it's actually recognized by the United Nations
そしてそれは実際に国連によって認められています
yes then so honestly
はい、それでは正直に言って
thank you very much for your speech today
今日はご講演いただきまして誠にありがとうございました
thank you for this
それが彼の感謝です
Thank you very much for your points
ポイントを頂き誠にありがとうございます
sorry
ごめん
that thank you so much for sharing
共有してくれて本当にありがとう
that is me
それは私です
Your sharing is actually
あなたの共有は実際には
in my feeling
私の気持ちでは
A very important part is to say
非常に重要な部分は次のとおりです
What Du Congming said at the time
その時杜聡明が言ったこと
from a certain point of view
ある角度から
On the one hand, we can say that it actually has a vision
一方で、実際にビジョンがあるとも言えます。
And conveniently, it can be said that this is still there today.
そして都合の良いことに、それは今でも残っていると言えます。
In justice, right?
正義においてですよね？
Now I kind of want to borrow
今ちょっと借りたいのですが
Do a self-reflection on what you just said
今言ったことを反省してください
That is to say, in fact, this is what we study
つまり、実際、これが私たちが研究していることなのです
History of Modern Traditional Medicine
現代伝統医学の歴史
a very special point
非常に特別な点
It's just that what we study is completely non-committal.
ただ、私たちが勉強していることはまったくコミットメントがありません。
As of today, there is no general conclusion
今日の時点では一般的な結論は出ていない
contemporary relevance
現代との関連性
Both sides are still in a high degree of justice
双方とも未だに高度な正義を保っている
such a situation
そのような状況
just say what i mean
私の言いたいことを言ってください
like the one just now
今のような
Vice President Liu introduced
劉副社長の紹介
I'm in a department of history of science
私は科学史学科に所属しています
get a doctorate
博士号を取得する
Then most of our friends have studied
それから私たちの友達のほとんどは勉強しました
That is to say, whether it is the history of physics or the history of biology
つまり、物理学の歴史であれ、生物学の歴史であれ、
when historians began to study the meaning of coming
歴史家が来たことの意味を研究し始めたとき
That is to say, things have been concluded
つまり物事は決着した
truth we already know
私たちがすでに知っている真実
That's called Ke Shuli
それは柯書里と呼ばれています
So what historians do is start with
したがって、歴史家が行うことは、以下から始めることです
we already know what the conclusion is
私たちはすでに結論を知っています
At least write back the angle of who won
少なくとも誰が勝ったかの角度を書き返してください
But only today I do this research
でも今日だけ私はこの研究をしています
From a certain point of view until today
ある視点から今日まで
There is also a tall one
高いのもあるよ
means uncertainty and truth
不確実性と真実を意味します
So I think on the one hand you feel
それで、一方ではあなたはこう感じていると思います
maybe a little resonant and inspiring
たぶん少し共鳴し、インスピレーションを与えるでしょう
But on the other hand we can also say
しかしその一方で、こうも言えます
the truth of this matter
この件の真実
we don't quite know yet
まだよくわかりません
and even i kinda want to
そして私でもちょっとそうしたいです
come further
さらに来てください
say play the bad guy
悪役を演じると言う
to say one thing
一つ言うこと
Actually from
実はから
Du Conghui
杜従輝より
Who he doesn't accept when he mentions these studies
彼がこれらの研究について言及するときに受け入れられない人
Locke
ロック
exist
存在
Some of the Union Hospital
ユニオン病院の一部
medical scientist
医学者
They think it's easy to understand
彼らはそれがわかりやすいと思っている
because he felt
彼は感じたから
You don't have any yin and yang elements
あなたには陰と陽の要素がありません
We also have 400 million say
我々にも4億の発言権がある
We also have very long science
私たちには非常に長い科学もあります
We also have a lot of medicines that people say are useful
効果があると言われている薬もたくさんあります
But since the end of the 19th century
しかし、19世紀末以降、
We did a large clinical study results
私たちは大規模な臨床研究の結果を出しました
proven medicine
証明された薬
Most of them are useless
それらのほとんどは役に立たない
that is
あれは
The American Medical Association was founded
アメリカ医師会が設立されました
A great feature is to say
大きな特徴は次のとおりです。
It turned out that the previous medical period was useless
前回の治療期間が無駄だったことが判明
So according to what I just said
それで、私が今言ったことによれば、
It is easy for them to regard Chinese medicine as
彼らにとって漢方薬は次のように捉えられやすいのです。
Same thing as their old medical
昔の医療と同じこと
So they also feel
それで彼らも感じます
we just did
私たちはたった今やったばかりです
After such a glorious revolution in medicine
医学におけるこのような輝かしい革命の後
Then know what medicine is useful
次に、どの薬が役立つかを知る
Then why should I waste my time on your side
それならなぜ私があなたの側で時間を無駄にしなければならないのですか
So what I mean is kind of saying
つまり、私が言いたいのは、ある種のことです
I want to echo your argument
あなたの主張を繰り返したい
is that this does have a high correlation
これは高い相関関係があるということです
But on the contrary, it also highlights that
しかし、それは逆に、次のことも強調しています。
As far as Du Congming is concerned, he wants to propose such an idea
杜聡明に関する限り、彼はそのようなアイデアを提案したいと考えています
even put into practice
実践することさえ
it was difficult
難しかったです
so
それで
If you feel wronged sometimes, you should
時々不当な扱いを受けていると感じる場合は、次のようにすべきです。
Think Du Congming should
杜聡明はそうすべきだと思う
He even became the dean of National Taiwan University Hospital and couldn't give classes later
彼は国立台湾大学病院の院長にもなったが、その後授業ができなくなった
I think all of us should be able to bear our grievances.
私たちは皆、不満を我慢できるべきだと思います。
That is to say, I kind of want to borrow this
つまり、これを借りたいのですが、
to say is to say
言うことは言うことです
In fact, one of the problems highlighted
実際、問題点の 1 つが浮き彫りになった
that is
あれは
a condition in progress
進行中の状態
yes
はい
Thank you Mr. Lei for your speech
レイ先生、ご講演ありがとうございました
Today's class is a little bit
今日の授業はちょっとだけ
Make up for the previous time in medical school
前回の医学部時代の埋め合わせ
did not read part of the history of medicine
医学の歴史の一部を読んでいない
When it comes to Chinese medicine and Western medicine, I want to learn
漢方と西洋医学のことを学びたい
The first lesson we have to learn is that to bet is to bet
私たちが学ばなければならない最初の教訓は、賭けることは賭けることであるということです
It kind of echoes your saying that Su Dongpo is a medical student.
蘇東坡は医学生だというあなたの言葉と似ていますね。
So be careful when using drugs
なので薬の使用には気をつけてください
In the research of Chinese and Western medicine, if we put the so-called positive attitude into research
中医学や西洋医学の研究において、いわゆる積極的な姿勢で研究をすると、
Perhaps in the part of western medicine, it emphasizes on getting rid of the bad effects first.
おそらく西洋医学の部分では、まず悪影響を取り除くことに重点が置かれています。
Don't treat people as experiments
人を実験台として扱うな
But Chinese medicine is a kind of comparative experiment
しかし、漢方薬は一種の比較実験です
It's empirical science, it's been used for thousands of years and it really works
これは経験科学であり、何千年も使用されており、実際に効果があります
For example, this three-legged branch
たとえば、この三本足の枝は
Like acupuncture and moxibustion in terms of anesthesia and pain relief
麻酔や鎮痛という点では鍼灸と同じです。
it has indeed been demonstrated
それは確かに実証されている
After the demonstration, the problem is that it will be a little controversial to study it with Western methods
デモンストレーションの後、問題はそれを西洋の方法で研究することは少し物議を醸すだろうということです
The biggest controversy is that it comes from the placebo effect
最大の論争はプラシーボ効果から来ているということだ
In fact, many medicines do not necessarily have to be effective, but they are effective when we see a doctor.
実際、必ずしも効果があるとは限らない薬も多くありますが、医師の診察を受けると効果が現れます。
Seeing a doctor is effective, so how to get rid of the placebo effect?
医師の診察が効果的ですが、プラセボ効果を取り除くにはどうすればよいでしょうか?
In Western medicine, it is relatively clear that it proposes the Shuangman experiment
西洋医学では、双満実験を提案していることは比較的明らかです。
Just like a doctor and a patient
まるで医者と患者のように
The patient doesn't know what the drug is
患者はその薬が何であるかを知りません
Then when comparing the two
次に、両者を比較すると、
Then prove it
じゃあ証明してみろよ
It's true that this drug is more effective than a placebo
この薬がプラセボより効果があるのは本当だ
that's called effective
それを効果的といいます
But what is really effective in medicine
しかし、医学で本当に効果があるものは何ですか
In fact, placebos are also effective
実はプラセボも効果がある
So from a medical point of view
したがって、医学的な観点から見ると、
You can also skip to see
スキップして見ることもできます
Traditional Chinese Medicine and Western Medicine
伝統的な中国医学と西洋医学
Whether it's a black cat or a white cat
黒猫でも白猫でも
It's a good cat to be able to catch him
彼を捕まえることができるのは良い猫です
sick
病気
Why is the placebo effect not considered effective?
なぜプラシーボ効果は効果的ではないと考えられるのでしょうか?
This is what we do in medical school
これが医学部でやっていることです
I often discuss whether I sold some medicine
私は薬を販売するかどうかについてよく話し合います
including food
食べ物も含めて
If the consumer finds it effective
消費者が効果があると感じれば
why don't you sell him
なぜ彼を売らないのですか
Selling the placebo effect is also a good effect
プラセボ効果を売りにするのも良い効果
So from a valid point of view
したがって、正当な観点からすると
That's what you said just now
それはあなたが今言ったことです
When viewed from another point of view
別の視点から見ると
he will show up and say
彼は現れて言うだろう
Nothing wrong with looking clinically effective
臨床的に効果があるように見えることに何も問題はありません
But after proof
しかし証拠を残した後、
Maybe he's the same as the placebo
もしかしたら彼もプラセボと同じなのかもしれない
That's also in medicine
それは医学でもある
Actually the subtle part
実は微妙な部分
so this controversy
だからこの論争は
I don't think it's easy
簡単なことではないと思います
When we want to use the words of traditional Chinese medicine
中医学の言葉を使いたいとき
I'm talking about Sashi
サシのことを言ってるんだよ
He mixes a lot of medicine
彼はたくさんの薬を調合します
So take out its components
それで、そのコンポーネントを取り出します
In fact, as my partner just said,
実際、私のパートナーが先ほど言ったように、
In fact, there are some other metabolites
実は他にも代謝物がいくつかあります
Might work
うまくいくかもしれない
But you only analyze the same time every time
しかし、毎回同じ時間しか分析しない
It doesn't actually prove that
それは実際には証明されていません
His effect comes from this ingredient
彼の効果はこの成分から来ています
Ephedrine is a special case
エフェドリンは特殊なケースです
happens to have one main ingredient
たまたま主成分が1つだけある
Then find its components from traditional medicine
次に、伝統医学からその成分を見つけます
This case is very rare
このケースは非常にまれです
Because the entire treatment process of traditional Chinese medicine
なぜなら、伝統的な中国医学の治療プロセス全体が
it's not that simple
それはそれほど単純ではありません
That's what I think our show today
今日のショーはそう思います
That is to say, in this topic
つまり、この話題では、
I really admire Dr. Du Congwen
私はドゥ・コンウェン博士を本当に尊敬しています
he was at that time
彼はその時だった
just what you said
あなたが言ったことだけ
he's on the edge
彼は崖っぷちにいる
then go find one
それから探しに行ってください
Quite able to become a main axis of the protagonist
かなり主人公の主軸になり得る
It's an interesting piece of history from this point of view.
この観点から見ても興味深い歴史です。
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you, Dr. Lei, for your wonderful speech today.
レイ博士、今日は素晴らしいスピーチをしていただきありがとうございました。
That's why I'm very interested in Dr. Du Congming's retrograde spellcasting
だからこそ私は杜聡明博士の逆行呪文にとても興味があるのです。
Because I think his is similar to our current transfer medicine to a certain extent
現在の転移薬とある程度似ていると思うので
Because transfer medicine is to combine basic and clinical research
なぜなら転移医学は基礎研究と臨床研究を組み合わせるからです
Of course, you can also start from the basics.
もちろん基礎から始めることも可能です。
Then find it effective and then apply it to animals
そして、それが効果的であることを発見し、動物に適用します
and then apply it to humans
そしてそれを人間に応用する
But we sometimes issue some phenomena clinically
しかし、私たちは臨床的にいくつかの現象を引き起こすことがあります
Then go back and talk about designing some experiments
それから戻って、いくつかの実験の計画について話します。
Let's see what the underlying mechanism is
根本的なメカニズムが何であるかを見てみましょう
Then you say that the matter of using people as experiments is not necessarily not on the CE level.
それから、人を実験台にするという問題は、必ずしもCEレベルではないということですね。
Like we sometimes use some off label use
適応外使用を時々使用するように
That is to say, if A is effective for disease A at the beginning
つまり、最初にAという病気にAが効果的であれば、
But we may accidentally find that it is also effective in B disease
しかし、偶然にもB型疾患にも効果があることがわかるかもしれません。
Then go back and see what the mechanism is.
次に戻って、そのメカニズムが何であるかを確認します。
So this is not necessarily an experiment with humans.
したがって、これは必ずしも人間を対象とした実験ではありません。
yes so i think this
はい、だから私はこう思います
In fact, I feel like what the gentleman said just now is to say
実際、私は紳士が今言ったことのように感じます
In fact, there may be many effective ingredients in traditional Chinese medicine.
実は漢方薬には有効成分がたくさんあるのかもしれません。
It's just that we haven't used some so-called
いわゆるいくつかのものを使用していないだけです
It's just a scientific method recognized by the West to formalize
それは西洋によって正式に認められた単なる科学的方法です
Thanks
ありがとう
I will respond first
まずはお返事させていただきます
The gentleman you just mentioned means that
あなたが今言った紳士は、つまり、
poison problem
毒物問題
In fact, what Mantre said is that
実際、マントル氏は次のように述べています。
Changshan is poison
長山就是毒
just say yes now
今すぐ「はい」と言ってください
And it is a poison in the compendium of this article
そして、それはこの記事の要約の毒です
also poisonous
毒もあります
So actually from this point of view
ですから実際にこの観点から見ると
there is a part that says
と言う部分があります
accumulated knowledge
蓄積された知識
Some knowledge about toxicity
毒性に関する知識
And later, like the one I just used by Chen Guofu
そしてその後、私が陳国福が使ったもののように
When he used it, he used to call it Jiemao Pill
彼がそれを使用していたとき、彼はそれをJiemao Pillと呼んでいた
He knows not to use it on pregnant women
彼は妊婦に使用してはいけないことを知っています
And this means that
そして、これが意味するのは、
Don't use it casually on others
他人にむやみに使わないでください
Because I know it's poisonous
毒があるのは分かっているから
You have to wait until someone's sadism is cured
誰かのサディズムが治るまで待たなければなりません
It's happened to a certain extent
ある程度はそうなったよ
In other words, you're more certain of his sadism.
言い換えれば、あなたは彼のサディズムをより確信しているということです。
But in fact he was
しかし実際には彼はそうでした
The way to cure the doctor will not be to torture the worm, right?
医者を治す方法は寄生虫を乱用しないことですよね？
at least when you're sure
少なくとも確信があるときは
You are only halfway to cure this disease
この病気を治すにはまだ道半ばです
in fact they
実際、彼らは
What I mean by this is that
これが言いたいのは、
you are right
あなたが正しいです
on the one hand that is
一方ではそれは
this is an important concern
これは重要な懸念事項です
But in fact, they have accumulated some
しかし実際には、彼らはある程度の蓄積を持っています
relevant knowledge
関連する知識
On the other hand, it is also the other way around.
一方で、その逆もあります。
directly like fruit skin
まるで果物の皮のように
when serving to others
他人に奉仕するとき
It's actually a bit dangerous.
実はちょっと危険なんです。
In addition to what you just said
今言ったことに加えて
Possible effect
考えられる影響
This is indeed a question that many people will ask
これは確かに多くの人が尋ねる質問です
But this kind of echoes
でも、この種のエコーは
the one in front
前にいる人
That lady, what you just said is that
あの女性、あなたが今言ったのは、
as far as i know
現在就我所知
That truth can indeed be applied to animals
その真実は確かに動物にも当てはまります
That is to say, it is already effective
つまり、すでに効果が出ているということです
not employing
雇用していない
not use human blood
人間の血液を使用しない
So this is actually a
これは実際には
just to say
ただ言うために
At least in animals
少なくとも動物においては
This must not be a possible effect
これは考えられる影響ではありません
It must be working for some other reason
何か別の理由で機能しているはずです
then
それから
The last thing you said was that
あなたが最後に言ったのは、
Actually Possible effect
実際に考えられる効果
also a good thing
良いことでもある
why would
なぜだろう
It means you do the two-chamber experiment
それは二室実験を行うことを意味します
Just take it as if to exclude it from your evaluation
評価から除外するかのように受け取ってください
You just said this
あなたは今こう言いました
Actually this
実はこれ
i know a case
私は事件を知っています
that's because
それは
That is to say, at Harvard University
つまりハーバード大学では
Their Otentative Medicine Office
臨時診療所
there is a researcher
研究者がいます
he is doing this research
彼はこの研究をしています
that is
あれは
Is it possible to think through this research
この研究を通じて考えることは可能ですか
How to strengthen placible effect
柔軟効果を強化する方法
That said, don't think of it as just
とはいえ、それを単なるものだと考えないでください
row measure out such a thing
行、そのようなものを測定します
Then this is a bit close to Du Congming's idea
そうすると、これは杜聡明の考えに少し近いですね。
It means we find something of value
それは価値のあるものを見つけることを意味します
to design new research methods
新しい研究方法を設計する
Then try to understand its possible function
次に、その可能な機能を理解しようとします
probably this is the case
おそらくこれが事実です
Thank you for the situation you just said
あなたが今言った状況に感謝します
I might have to ask you
あなたに尋ねなければならないかもしれません
I have heard it many times
何度も聞いたことがあります
but i don't know very well
でもよく分からない
The details of that translation medicine
その翻訳医学の詳細
so i'll ask you again
だからもう一度聞いてみます
Thanks
ありがとう
I am after chemistry
私は化学を追いかけています
I have always been interested in Chinese medicine
もともと漢方薬に興味があったのですが、
but never had a chance to do it
でもそれをする機会がなかった
I thought about doing some research to help
いくつか調べてみようと思いました
Then I switched to immunity
それから免疫に切り替えました
Finally I learned fine medicine
ついに素晴らしい医学を学びました
so in fact i am
だから実際私はそうだ
The main character is you so I don't want to talk about myself
主人公はあなただから自分のことは語りたくない
No, then just a dermatologist
いいえ、それならただの皮膚科医です
That is also to continue to have an extreme interest in Chinese medicine
それは中医学に強い関心を持ち続けることでもある
but never had a chance to do
でもやる機会がなかった
One after another, the views on Chinese and English are not the same
中国と英国に対する見解の相違も相次いでいる。
Then the research is not the same
それでは研究は同じではありません
So I'm thinking I've gained a lot today
だから今日はたくさんのことを得ることができたと思う
i was thinking
私が考えていた
in fact you may have said
実際、あなたは言ったかもしれません
this mystery this is
この謎はこれだ
I'm talking about whether he was at that time
私は彼がその時いたかどうかについて話しています
Because he wrote the 60,000
彼が60,000を書いたからです
very amazing
非常に素晴らしいです
he wrote sixty thousand
彼は6万書いた
but he skimmed the words of the book
しかし彼は本の言葉をざっと読んだ
Probably not necessarily 100 times, 100 times
おそらく100回、100回とは限らない
he may have this amazing ability
彼はこの驚くべき能力を持っているかもしれない
able to see
見える
Then he read the history of the nations
それから彼は国々の歴史を読みました
so he saw some evidence base
それで彼はいくつかの証拠を見た
There was no Clean your trial
試用版をクリーンアップする機能はありませんでした
But finally I keep feeling
でも最終的には感じ続けている
There is no evidence base
証拠根拠がない
not gone
消えていない
it works
できます
did not do trial
裁判はしなかった
But looking at the words of thousands of years
でも何千年の言葉を見てみると
Grandfather began to say
おじいさんが言い始めた
In the end, in fact, there can be evidence
結局のところ、実際には証拠が見つかる可能性があります
Are you looking at history?
歴史を見ていますか？
Articles written by Congming
孔明が書いた記事
It can be seen that he saw some often an example
彼がよく見たのはその一例であることがわかります
Maybe there are other examples
もしかしたら他にも例があるかもしれない
So of course he speaks in English
もちろん彼は英語で話します
intrigue
陰謀
He thinks it works
彼はそれがうまくいくと思っている
so he saw this
それで彼はこれを見た
so he saw some evidence
それで彼はいくつかの証拠を見ました
Then he said he was going to push
それから彼は押すつもりだと言いました
And said he believes that all Chinese medicines are effective
そして、彼はすべての漢方薬が効果があると信じていると言いました
but it will work
でもそれはうまくいきます
So if you look at those with more evidence
ですから、より多くの証拠があるものを見てみると、
for research
研究用
It should work like this
このように動作するはずです
this is
これは
eight door farmer
エイトドアファーマー
so i thought this i wanted to find out
それで私はこれを知りたかったと思いました
Is there such a possibility in history?
歴史上、そのような可能性はあるのでしょうか？
maybe what you just said
たぶんあなたが今言ったこと
i just didn't hear fully
完全に聞き取れなかっただけです
The second is the fact that traditional Chinese medicine needs to last until the end
2つ目は、漢方薬は最後まで続ける必要があるということです。
in fact it should be
実際そうあるべきです
If it is a chemical drug
化学薬品なら
It is what we made and traditional Chinese medicine
私たちが作った漢方薬です
It is the identity in Chinese medicine
それが中国医学の正体です
all chemicals
すべての化学物質
chemicals are the same thing
化学薬品も同じものです
It's not like something made in a lab
実験室で作られたものとは違います
is a chemical
化学物質です
inside the plant
工場内
So it's another
それで、それは別です
are likely to be the same
同じである可能性が高い
in fact it is
実際それは
Like for example Tuxol these all become
たとえばトゥクソールのように、これらはすべて次のようになります。
Later, some medicines from western medicine practitioners
その後、西洋医学家からいくつかの薬が
So in fact it should be the same
したがって、実際には同じであるはずです
The second is
2つ目は
Now I feel more and more
今、私はますます感じています
suck a lot
たくさん吸う
Just relying on one medicine may not be enough
一つの薬に頼るだけでは不十分かもしれない
so it is always needed
だからそれは常に必要です
Just use combination
組み合わせて使うだけ
that so
まあまあ
So here's the word
それで、ここに言葉があります
In fact, Chinese medicine can be a kind of
実際、漢方薬は一種の
the therapy
治療法
or because i learned a word
または単語を覚えたから
Another person is interested in Chinese medicine
もう一人は中医学に興味がある
he too
彼もです
Too
それも
is that he is totally
それは彼が完全にそうだということです
evidence-based research scientist
証拠に基づいた研究科学者
But he also intrigued
しかし、彼も興味をそそられました
He said this is complex formulation like this
彼は、これはこのような複雑な定式化であると言いました
So by the end of the two probably will be in
だから、終わりまでに2人はおそらくそうなるだろう
will be merge together
一緒にマージされます
Then I just talked about evidence-based
それから私は証拠に基づいたものについて話しました
It was just mentioned by the director
さっき監督が言ってた
is in fact
実際のところ
That is to say
つまり
In fact it is
実際そうなのです
It is not said to be a real clinical trial
本当の臨床試験とは言えません
But for thousands of years
しかし、何千年もの間、
It's a trial
裁判だよ
so many years
何年も
Xi Yiduo hasn't done it yet
Xi Yiduoはまだやっていません
FDA approval can be obtained in about a few years
FDAの承認は数年程度で取得可能
But this has been done for thousands of years
しかし、これは何千年も行われてきました
get some effective
効果を得る
not all will work
すべてがうまくいくわけではありません
So my previous build looks like this
私の以前のビルドは次のようになります
maybe repeat what you said
あなたが言ったことを繰り返すかもしれません
But I think when people live
でも、人が生きていく上で思うのは、
Learn my thoughts from you a little bit
私の考えをあなたから少し学んでください
It feels really late today
今日は本当に遅く感じます
So let's try and talk more later
それで、後でもっと話しましょう
Or we can set up a club to discuss this matter
あるいは、この問題について話し合うクラブを設立することもできます
I'm sorry, of course I'd rather
ごめんなさい、もちろんそうしたいです
ask the professor
教授に聞く
Just now we talked about Chinese medicine and Western medicine
先ほど、中医学と西洋医学についてお話しました。
In our impression, that is to say, most people
私たちの印象では、つまりほとんどの人は、
modern scientific treatment
現代の科学的治療
Western medicine speed treatment is relatively fast
西洋医学のスピード治療は比較的早い
Chinese medicine treatment appears to be more
漢方治療がさらに進むようです
slower version slower better
遅いバージョンの方が遅いほど良い
What kind of concept
どのようなコンセプトですか
Is this thinking correct?
この考えは正しいでしょうか?
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you, let me respond first
ありがとう、まずは返信させてください
The question raised by Liu Feiyang just now
先ほど劉飛洋が提起した質問
you just mentioned that
あなたは今それを言いました
that is to say ducong
つまりデューコン
That is to say actually
つまり実際には
Yes, I think Du is smart
はい、ドゥは賢いと思います
Du Congming is actually on this matter
杜聡明は実際にこの問題に取り組んでいます
he has a very scientific stance
彼は非常に科学的な立場を持っています
which means there is no doubt that we can feel
つまり、私たちは感じることができることに疑いの余地はありません
He feels the value of traditional Chinese medicine or traditional Chinese medicine
彼は伝統的な中国医学または伝統的な中国医学の価値を感じています
There's actually more to it than we know now
実際には、私たちが今知っている以上のことがたくさんあります
So he wants to develop a new research method
そこで彼は新しい研究方法を開発したいと考えています
But how much he wasn't sure
しかし、彼はどれほど確信していなかったのか
So he says there are three possible futures
つまり、彼は 3 つの可能性のある未来があると言っています
he was the first to say
彼が最初に言った
If you find a lot of value
たくさんの価値を見つけたら
we really did
私たちは本当にやった
That is to say, there is no Effidence
つまり、根拠がないのです
We really do find a lot of value
私たちは本当に多くの価値を見出しています
He said we should put it in medical school
彼はそれを医学部に入れるべきだと言いました
let students take electives
生徒に選択科目を取らせる
It is the situation of the hospital of traditional Chinese medicine we just talked about
先ほどお話しした中医院の状況です。
The second is to say
2つ目は、こう言うことです
We found that only a few were valuable
価値があるものはほんのわずかであることがわかりました
In fact, most of them are worthless
実際、それらのほとんどは無価値です
Then a small part should be incorporated into western medicine.
そして、西洋医学に少しだけ取り入れればいいのです。
The third is that you find not only worthless
3つ目は、自分には価値がないだけではないということです
many worthless
多くの価値のない
And it's toxic
そしてそれは有毒です
He said you should quickly announce it to the public
彼はそれを世間に公表すべきだと言いました
Tell everyone not to use
みんなに使わないように言いなさい
He said that because everyone is busy using
みんなが使うのに忙しいから、と彼は言いました。
It's not good now
今は良くない
So he actually has a pretty open stance.
つまり、彼は実際にはかなりオープンなスタンスを持っています。
Now open to outside positions
社外ポジションも募集中
you can really feel it
本当にそれを感じることができます
He thinks it's definitely worth more than we know now
彼はそれが私たちが今知っているよりも間違いなく価値があると考えています
And now I know from Changshan's standpoint
そして今、私は常山の立場から知っています
he does know
彼は知っています
Then he talked about massage, snake medicine, etc.
それからマッサージやヘビ薬などについて話しました。
So he should have some personal energy
だから彼には個人的なエネルギーがあるはずだ
That is to say, the value is relatively high.
つまり、相対的に値が高いということです。
Then this is connected to what you just said
それから、これはあなたが今言ったことにつながります
In fact, most of us now feel that
実際、私たちのほとんどは今、次のように感じています。
Chinese medicine seems to be a chronic disease, right?
漢方って慢性病っぽいですよね？
It can be seen that Du Congming's move is infectious disease
杜聡明の動きは感染症であることがわかる
It means the saddle
サドルという意味です
So in fact, at that time
それで実はその時、
You think that when there is no Western medicine, Chinese medicine must be an acute disease
西洋医学がないのに漢方薬は急性疾患に違いないと思っている
Therefore, it is much slower than what we now teach Chinese medicine.
したがって、私たちが現在教えている中国医学よりもはるかに遅いです。
Some are actually relative to this history after
いくつかは実際にその後の歴史に関連しています
Because you have to compare with the pressure given to you by Western medicine
西洋医学が与える圧力と比較する必要があるため
You have to maintain an idea that you have created
自分で作ったアイデアは維持しなければなりません
It's not exactly the original historical situation
それは正確には元の歴史的状況ではありません
that's probably the case
おそらくそうだろう
In addition, Chairman Liu Feihong, what you just mentioned is that
さらに、劉飛紅会長、今おっしゃったのは、
In fact, it could be a problem of drug mixing.
実際、それは薬物の混合の問題である可能性があります。
Christian Zongming specifically mentioned that
クリスチャン・ゾンミンは特に次のように言及しました
not only did he say
彼は言っただけでなく
we can do it in reverse
逆にできます
experimental therapeutics
実験的治療法
Then do it first on people
それならまず人にやってみろよ
And he said that unit medicine is not necessary
そして彼は単位医療は必要ないと言いました
he said he would
彼はそうすると言った
He even gave many examples saying
彼は多くの例を挙げてこう言いました
why he imagined
なぜ彼は想像したのか
The effect of the medicine after several medicines get together
複数の薬が集まってからの薬の効果
Possibility of altered potency
効力が変化する可能性
So in this sense
ですから、そういう意味では
He did mention it early
彼は早い段階でそれについて言及しました
what we think today
今日私たちが考えていること
It is not necessary to pursue the goal of unit drug
必ずしも医薬品単位の目標を追求する必要はない
Then this point at the time
そうするとこの時点で
Japan has begun to change
日本は変わり始めた
that's probably sober
それはおそらく地味だ
right
右
ask the professor
教授に聞く
Just now we said that poison
たった今、毒について言いました
That's what many of our concepts mean
それが私たちのコンセプトの多くが意味するものです
Many diseases sometimes require
多くの病気では、必要な場合があります。
Fighting poison with poison isn't it?
毒をもって毒を制す、ですね。
that is to say
つまり
we have many cypresses
うちにはヒノキがたくさんあります
Unified thoughts
統一した考え
Many people think that traditional Chinese medicine is more
多くの人は伝統的な漢方薬のほうがいいと思っています。
Suitable for conditioning this vitality
この活力を整えるのに適しています
It is faster to use C1 to treat diseases
病気の治療にはC1を使用した方が早い
Is this the right idea, thanks
これは正しい考えですか、ありがとう
In fact, I think what you just said is very complicated and interesting.
実際、今おっしゃったことは非常に複雑で興味深いと思います。
The first one is that your first sentence is actually
1 つ目は、最初の文が実際には
Hu Ying, what the gentleman said just now is that if it is poisonous, right?
胡英、紳士が今言ったのは、毒があるならということですよね？
So from a certain point of view it must be
したがって、ある観点から見ると、それはそうあるに違いありません
Must be toxic, use with care
有毒である必要があるため、注意して使用してください
Then I remembered another thing you said, that is,
それから私はあなたが言ったもう一つのことを思い出しました。
In my research I have asked for advice that is
研究の中で私が求めたアドバイスは、
Now to the Dean Zhang Henghong of Taichung Chinese Medical College
さて、台中中国医科大学の張恒紅学部長へ
At that time, he was the director of Changgen's Institute of Traditional Medicine
当時、彼はチャンゲン伝統医学研究所の所長でした。
He is promoting the notification system of adverse reactions of traditional Chinese medicine
漢方薬の副作用報告制度を推進している
He said Taiwanese are
彼は台湾人はこう言った
is the most messy eater
最も汚い人です
Because just saying it all has no side effects
全部言うだけで副作用はないから
eat as food
食べ物として食べる
But in fact, if he was used as medicine before, it must be effective
でも実際、かつて薬として使われていたのなら、きっと効果があるはずだ
So in fact maybe I because I don't have one
実際、私は持っていないからかもしれません
Notification system for adverse drug reactions
医薬品副作用通知制度
so you don't know what bad effects it has
だからそれがどんな悪影響をもたらすか分からない
So this is actually a
これは実際には
I just said
私はちょうど言いました
If you originally came to see the food therapy tradition of Chinese medicine
もともと中国医学の伝統的な食事療法を見に来たのであれば
Many are real
多くは本物です
I think this food can be used as medicine
この食べ物は薬として使えると思う
So some things you can't be careful about
そのため、注意できないこともあります
But now we feel like saying
でも今はこう言いたい気分です
Chinese medicine is consistent with chronic
漢方薬は慢性疾患と一致します
all itchy
全部かゆい
Then did not eat fitness
それからフィットネスは食べませんでした
It's okay to eat
食べても大丈夫です
That is to say, it is actually somewhat
つまり、実際にはある程度です
It wouldn't be what people thought a hundred years ago
それは百年前の人々が考えていたことではないでしょう
So the other way around
それで逆に
For example, like the Dean Zhang Wenhong I just mentioned
たとえば、先ほど述べた張文紅学部長のように。
The adverse reaction system of traditional Chinese medicine that he wants to promote
彼が広めたい漢方薬の副作用システム
In fact, it is also equivalent to one of the modernization of traditional Chinese medicine.
実はそれは現代の中国医学に相当します。
important step
重要なステップ
probably like this
おそらくこんな感じ
Dr Ray I'm sorry please
レイ博士、ごめんなさい
i want to ask
聞きたいです
I just mentioned that young boy from that continent
先ほどあの大陸から来たあの少年のことを言いました
What part of the study is decantin
デカンチンは研究のどの部分ですか
it is this part of the research conduct program
これは研究実施プログラムの一部です
marry us or something
私たちと結婚するか何か
can you add
追加していただけますか
let me compare to this
これと比べてみましょう
where is he
彼はどこにいますか
With our present set is
当店のプレゼントセットには、
relatively similar or
比較的似ているか、
he is part of some inspiration
彼はインスピレーションの一部です
isn't it
ではない？
right
右
because we didn't mention
私たちが言及しなかったから
said he actually had
彼は実際に持っていたと言いました
it's me right
それは私です
because i'm a layman
私は素人なので
i don't know
わからない
that is to say he
つまり彼は
Is there a certain part of the program
プログラムの特定の部分はありますか
There is also a breakthrough
突破口もあるよ
and come in from a different point of view
そして違う視点から入ってくる
i don't know much
私はあまり知りません
This time Nobel talks about his
今回ノーベルは彼のことについて語ります。
talk to one of our local
地元の人に相談してください
may need to be supplemented
補足する必要があるかもしれません
let me know something
何か教えてください
Thank you
ありがとう
Well actually you asked a very good question
そうですね、実際、あなたはとても良い質問をしました
And it's a question I really want to know
そしてそれは私が本当に知りたい質問です
that's what i think you're feeling
それがあなたが感じていることだと思います
The story of the long mountain I just told
さっき話した長い山の話
There's a lot of element of surprise, right?
驚きの要素がたくさんありますよね？
Very different from 12345
12345とは大きく異なります
But the story of Qinghaosu
しかし、チンハオスの物語
Right now the act of righteousness is here
正義の行為が今ここにある
Because when Nobel speaks
ノーベルが話すときだから
He is not awarded to Chinese medicine, right?
彼は中医学の賞を受賞したわけではないですよね？
He is awarded for the study of a modern science
彼は現代科学の研究で賞を受賞した
as if to say
まるで言うかのように
can happen anywhere
どこでも起こり得る
Research that any scientist can come and do
科学者なら誰でも来て研究を行うことができます
And there are plenty of critics who will say
そしてこう言う批評家もたくさんいる
This is actually the CCP’s
これは実際には中国共産党のものです
The needs of the Vietnam War
ベトナム戦争の必要性
Invest a lot of resources in the country for auditions, right?
オーディションのために国に多額のリソースを投資しますよね？
Then found a lot of drugs to conduct research
それから研究を行うためにたくさんの薬を見つけました
This is completely a typical process of new drug development
これはまさに新薬開発の典型的なプロセスです
Nothing to do with Chinese medicine
漢方薬とは関係ありません
So this is not Chinese medicine
つまりこれは漢方薬ではありません
you just kinda wanted to ask me this
あなたはちょうど私にこれを聞きたかったのです
so i'm going to be frank
だから率直に言うよ
That is to say, because Tuyou TV is actually involved in the controversy over Shenwei's award
つまり、Tuyou TVは実際にShenwei氏の受賞をめぐる論争に関与しているためである。
So the information we have seen so far is not complete.
したがって、これまでに見てきた情報は不完全です。
But I can at least know a few things
でも少なくともいくつかのことは分かるよ
first thing to say
最初に言うこと
We just told this story
この話をしたばかりです
when this is not a political decision
これが政治的決定ではない場合
Then I said it like this
そしたらこんな風に言いました
Now, for example, after Tuyoushi happened
さて、たとえば、Tuyoushiが起こった後、
If we look at the New York Times report
ニューヨーク・タイムズの報道を見てみると
would say that this is a typical scientific study
これは典型的な科学研究だと言えるでしょう
nothing weird, right?
何も変なことはありませんよね？
If we take the story of Changshan just now as an example
先ほどの常山の話を例にとると、
That doesn't sound like a typical science study
それは典型的な科学研究とは思えません
Instead, it involves breakthroughs in some scientific research methods
その代わりに、いくつかの科学的研究方法における画期的な進歩が含まれています。
only results
そうすることしかできない結果
You ask me this question again, right?
またこの質問をしますよね？
So now we put this story back into this history
だから今、私たちはこの物語をこの歴史に戻します
prompt people to start looking for
人々に探し始めるよう促す
Looking for anti-abuse drugs in China and Australia
中国とオーストラリアで乱用防止薬を探す
In fact, it is related to the atypical story of Changshan
実はこれは常山の異常な物語と関係があるのです。
Then according to a
それから、あるところによれば、
Now why on earth would you find
さて、いったいなぜ見つけるのでしょうか
Ching Pao Su's story
チン・パオ・スーの物語
I recently read one that just came out
最近出たばかりの本を読みました
That is, a verbal interview for this 523 plan
つまり、この523計画に対する口頭インタビューです。
Someone made a visit of hundreds of pages
誰かが数百ページにアクセスしました
Then I read it and felt like saying
それで読んでて言いたくなった
And I think that's what the author intended
それが作者の言いたかったことだと思う
That is to say, the credit is not
つまり、クレジットはありません
It shouldn't be Tu Youyou
トゥ・ヨウヨウではないはずだ
Because to a large extent another scholar
なぜなら、ほとんどの場合、別の学者が
He quickly put this screened list
彼はすぐにこの選別リストを作成しました
reduced to a dozen miles
数十マイルに短縮
Then it already contained the cleaning paraffin at that time
その時点ですでに洗浄パラフィンが含まれていました
And the scholar himself
そして学者自身も
Doing this screening can effectively
このスクリーニングを行うことで効果的に
In the process of narrowing down the objects of screening
審査対象を絞り込んでいる最中
A large part of him has been using Changshan since then.
それ以来、彼の大部分は常山を使用しています。
as a reference point
基準点として
in his opinion
彼の意見では
Because traditional Chinese medicine obviously
なぜなら伝統的な漢方薬は明らかに
Already found an effective drug against sadism
サディズムに効果的な薬はすでに発見されている
so it's hard for him to imagine saying
だから彼がこう言うのは想像しにくい
without
それなし
later
後で
Maybe there will be later
もしかしたら後もあるかもしれない
So he took the recipe with Changshan in it and took it away
そこで彼は常山が入ったレシピを持ち去った
Because of this, because those prescriptions are likely to mean
このため、それらの処方箋は次のことを意味する可能性が高いため、
is proven effective because of Chang Shan
チャンシャンのおかげで効果的であることが証明されています
Then it is looking for the common ground in the middle
次に、その中間にある共通点を探します
and help it focus to
そして、集中できるように手助けします
That is to say, the study of Qinghaosu
つまり、チンハオスの研究です。
So my answer to your question just now is to say
したがって、今のあなたの質問に対する私の答えは次のとおりです
My answer to you just now is to say
今のあなたへの私の答えはこう言います
1. I don’t have a story similar to Changshan to tell Haosu
1. ハオスに話す常山に似た話はない
Because there's a lot of historical material for that story
その話のソースはたくさんあるから
I have never seen
今まで見たこともない
But I based on oral interviews done by others
しかし、私は他の人による口頭インタビューに基づいています
A very detailed oral interview
非常に詳細な口頭面接
i think this thing
私はこのことを思う
At least part of it is
少なくともその一部は、
At that time, Tuluo could quickly narrow down the screening
そのとき、Tuluo はすぐにスクリーニングを絞り込むことができました
When screening Chinese medicine items
漢方薬の品目を審査する場合
In fact, it is used
実際に使われているのは、
That is to say, related to related matters
つまり、関連事項に関連して
But I can't explain the details more clearly.
しかし、詳細をこれ以上明確に説明することはできません。
so
それで
So in the story just now, I can only say that there is no way
だから今の話では仕方ないとしか言​​えない
Said that this is a story completely parallel to Changshan
これは常山と完全に並行する物語であると述べた
Teacher, I am very grateful for your speech today
先生、今日は本当にありがとうございました
And so the story about Tu Youyou's Nobel Prize
そしてトゥ・ヨウヨウのノーベル賞の話
Then I want to add this paragraph
次に、この段落を追加したいと思います
In fact, the Nobel Prize was awarded to Tu Youyou at the same time
実は同時期に屠友佑氏もノーベル賞を受賞している
Their works that won the Nobel Prize in Physiology and Medicine that year
その年のノーベル生理学・医学賞を受賞した彼らの研究
Also included was awarded to Mork for his original invention
モークの独創的な発明に対して授与されたものも含まれています
It's the medicine for blindness in Africa.
アフリカの失明治療薬です。
Right, and so the Nobel Prize committee judges
そうですね、ノーベル賞委員会の審査員もそうです
They themselves said they didn't award those two drugs
彼ら自身は、これら2つの薬物を授与していないと述べた
they awarded
彼らは授与した
In fact, what they're awarding is the method that actually discovered the drug in the first place.
実際、彼らが賞を与えているのは、そもそもその薬を実際に発見した方法です。
Then 10 years ago, the academicians of the Chinese Academy of Sciences opposed
そして10年前、中国科学院の学者たちは反対した。
it's important
それは重要です
But in fact, they should not have the academicians of Academia Sinica to remember
しかし実際には、中央研究院の学者たちに覚えてもらうべきではない。
During the Cultural Revolution
文化大革命の頃
Then those were sent out of the mainland
その後、彼らは本土から追い出されました
Then to those chemists in America
それからアメリカの化学者たちへ
In fact, many of them were taken in by Mokda Pharmaceuticals' laboratory in New York.
実際、それらの多くはニューヨークにあるモクダ製薬の研究所に引き取られました。
Yes, and in fact, Mokda and the others are very interested in Chinese medicine.
はい、そして実際、モクダたちは中国医学に非常に興味を持っています。
Then they also silently protect this piece
そして彼らもこの作品を黙って守る
yes then so
はい、それでは
Then the award to Tuyouyou should be in 2011
となると、Tuyouyou への受賞は 2011 年になるはずだ
Then other recapitalization at that time
その後、当時のその他の資本増強
Because he is actually very interested in making medicine
なぜなら彼は実際に薬を作ることに非常に興味があるからです
Yes and he is also right
はい、彼も正しいです
He is interested in making vaccines and then public health
彼はワクチンの製造、そして公衆衛生に興味を持っています
He is very interested in making medicine
彼は薬を作ることにとても興味があります
And then they already said
そして彼らはすでにこう言いました
In fact, it should be awarded to China
本当は中国に与えられるべきだ
It's the Chinese medicine
それは漢方薬です
Yes, then who will it be awarded to?
はい、それでは誰に授与されるのでしょうか？
At that time, I actually thought of Tuyouyou at first.
実はその時、最初はTuyouyouのことを考えたんです。
But it's not because he invented
でもそれは彼が発明したからではない
one word sadism drug
一言サディズムドラッグ
because what they really want to praise is
なぜなら彼らが本当に褒めたいのは、
The quick help in traditional Chinese medicine
すぐに役立つ伝統的な中国医学
how do you tell the difference
違いはどうやってわかりますか
how are we going to stuff it
どうやって詰めようか
Those who have been tired by the Lord for thousands of years
何千年も主に疲れさせられてきた人たち
The Chinese advocate the wisdom of getting tired first
中国人はまず疲れるという知恵を提唱している
What they're actually giving awards for is that set of things
彼らが実際に賞を与えているのはその一連のことです
Yeah, and because there's a lot of politics involved
そうですね、政治が大きく絡んでいるからです
you can't tell the truth
あなたは真実を言うことができません
We want to praise those who because Wenger
私たちはベンゲル監督の功績を讃えたい。
those assets that were then sent to the United States
その後米国に送られたこれらの資産
Yes, so I can only tell everyone
そう、だからみんなにだけ言えます
what we want to commend is
私たちが褒めたいのは
can help you quickly find
すぐに見つけるのに役立ちます
Approaches to new drug development
新薬開発への取り組み
this set
このセット
That's Nobel's Lecture
それがノーベル講演です
They said it themselves
彼ら自身がそう言ったのです
I haven't heard
聞いていない
and such words
そしてそのような言葉
This story is the opposite of what we usually hear
この話は私たちが普段聞いている話とは真逆です
right
右
these actually exist
これらは実際に存在します
And there are people who will remember this passage
この部分を覚えている人もいるでしょう
Because who protected those chemists in the first place?
だって、そもそも誰が化学者たちを守ったの？
top decision-makers
最高の意思決定者
In fact, there are still people from this world
実はこの世界にはまだ人がいる
right then
すぐに
So these stories are
ですから、これらの物語は、
someone is willing to admit
誰かが喜んで認めてくれる
Then they can
そうすれば、彼らはできる
was recorded
記録されました
then in fact
それから実際には
Nobel talks about how they award
ノーベル賞受賞の仕組みについて語る
Meaning they want to speed up
つまり彼らはスピードを上げたいのです
New steps to be developed
開発される新たなステップ
because now everyone says
今はみんなが言うから
new development
新しい開発
The process is too long
プロセスが長すぎます
Then it's because the process is too long
それはプロセスが長すぎるからです
So the price of new drugs will become very expensive
そのため新薬の価格は非常に高価になる
then you get expensive
そうすると高価になります
No matter how good the medicine you make
どんなに良い薬を作ったとしても
And then the problem is that it becomes a new drug
そして問題はそれが新薬になることです
we can't afford it
私たちにはそれを買う余裕がない
every country says so
どこの国もそう言うよ
Right, and so in fact what they want to change is
そうです、そして実際に彼らが変えたいのは
This whole thing is almost on the verge of collapse.
このすべてはほぼ崩壊の危機に瀕しています。
health care and medicine system
医療と医療システム
thanks i'm very interested
ありがとう、興味があります
I hope you will provide me with that information later
後ほどその情報を提供していただければ幸いです
Because I don't know what you just said
あなたが今何を言ったか分からないから
Then my impression is quite different
そうするとかなり印象が違います
so i'm curious to know more
だからもっと知りたいです
Thanks
ありがとう
Teacher, if I have found the information
先生、情報を見つけたら
i can send you a letter
あなたに手紙を送ることができます
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
teacher this gentleman
先生、この紳士
Teacher, thank you for this talk
先生、今回はお話ありがとうございました
In fact, your article is about Teacher Du Congming
実際、あなたの記事は杜聡明先生についてのものです
I got it by accident
偶然手に入れました
Then I just want to ask a question, that is
そこでちょっと質問したいのですが、
There is an appreciation for Chinese medicine formed by Dr. Du Congming
杜聡明博士によって形成された中国医学への感謝の気持ちがある
Then continue the research on medicines and medicines
その後も医学や医学の研究を続ける
the idea
このアイデア
Are you sure about the idea? Are there any related materials now?
このアイデアについてはよろしいでしょうか?今、関連する資料はありますか?
Explain that in fact, his thinking has actually changed.
実際、彼の考え方が実際に変わったことを説明します。
For example, he might be like Mr. Fussian from before
たとえば、以前のフーシアンさんのような人かもしれません。
Or a person like Mr. Sun Zhongan who upholds this careless position
あるいは、孫仲安氏のような、この軽率な立場を支持する人物
It’s just that he was like what Mr. Li you just said, he may have some experience in life
ただ、彼は今あなたが言った李さんのような人でした、彼は人生経験があるかもしれません
or some of his scientific intuition or something
あるいは彼の科学的直観か何か
Or it is such a belief in Chinese medicine in this battlefield formed by his Open Minded
あるいは、この戦場における漢方に対する信念は、彼のオープンマインドによって形成されたものだ
Is there a set of relevant materials that can be searched for again?
再度検索できる関連資料のセットはありますか?
How did he form a process of talking about traditional Chinese medicine on the battlefield
彼は戦場で漢方薬について語るプロセスをどのように形成したのか
Actually, I think this is Mr. Li, your speech today is very interesting.
実は、これは李さんだと思うのですが、今日のあなたのスピーチはとても興味深いです。
In fact, I think that in daily life, everyone will face
実際、日常生活の中で誰でも直面すると思います。
Especially including yourself or relatives or friends
特にあなた自身、親戚、友人を含む
When they face this kind of B-Pool of disease
この種の B プールの病気に直面したとき
will still face this so-called dispute between Chinese and Western medicine.
中国医学と西洋医学の間のいわゆる論争に今後も直面するだろう。
Including the treatment of the recent colorectal cancer of Mr. Su Geliang
蘇格良氏の最近の結腸直腸がんの治療も含めて
In fact, we can also clearly see that one is a pancake.
実際、1 つはパンケーキであることもはっきりとわかります。
I don't want to go to Western medicine again
もう西洋医学には行きたくない
Another position is that
もう一つの立場は、
probably in the modernized this
おそらくこれは近代化されたものです
Under this generality of modernity
このような現代性の普遍性の下で
I just insist on western medicine and I don't accept it
私は西洋医学を主張するだけで、それを受け入れません
Such an award for variety shows
バラエティ番組にとってはこんな賞
so i was thinking
それで私は考えていました
In fact, as far as I am concerned
実際、私に関する限りでは、
when myself
私自身のとき
Make this medical decision for yourself
この医学的決定はご自身で行ってください
or for example parents
または例えば両親
make such medical decisions
そのような医学的決定を下す
I still feel like saying
まだ言いたい気分
I should still be
私はまだそうあるべきです
Looking for this western doctor
この西洋人医師を探しています
Such a normal pipeline
このような通常のパイプライン
For example, in the context of this treatment
たとえば、この治療の文脈で言えば、
Follow the path of Western medicine
西洋医学の道を歩む
Because at least for Chinese medicine
少なくとも漢方薬に関しては
i may not understand
理解できないかもしれない
Or just don't have that much
それともそんなに持ってないのか
say maybe for some kind of cancer
おそらくある種の癌のせいだと思います
or gastroenteritis or something
胃腸炎か何か
such an unusual disease
そんな珍しい病気
Then does Chinese medicine have to have curative effect?
では、漢方薬には治療効果があるのでしょうか？
Actually I don't
実際にはそうではありません
If and when I have the right to make this decision
私にこの決定を下す権利がある場合、いつ
I would actually be like
私は実際には次のようになります
Mr. Fu Silin or Mr. Lu Xun said the same
傅思林氏や魯迅氏も同じことを言っていた
I won't make that decision
私はその決断はしません
But in the daily health care or food
しかし、日々の健康管理や食事においては、
Maybe we will often drink bitter tea
たぶん私たちは苦いお茶をよく飲むことになるでしょう
or herbal tea
またはハーブティー
but those are
しかしそれらは
The Doubtful Orders of Traditional Chinese Medicine
疑わしい漢方薬の指令
I feel like I can do it again
またできる気がする
such an absorption
そんな吸収
So actually answer one
それで実際に一つ答えてください
it's fun
楽しいです
This dispute between China and the West
中国と西側諸国との間のこの紛争
like before i thought
考える前のように
It seems that it is also in life
人生にもあるようです
inspired by something
何かに触発されて
just remind me of that
それを思い出してください
Academician Tian Changning talked about
学者の田長寧氏は次のように語った。
He said that he felt micro-learning was going to extremes
彼はマイクロラーニングが極端になりつつあると感じたと述べた
Is the research to do extreme
極限まで追求する必要があるのは研究です
Pursue excellence
追求卓越
It seems to be moderate on Weiren
ウェイレンは節度を持ったほうが良さそうですね
But for us now
でも今の私たちにとっては
From the point of view of the present
現在の視点から見ると
It seems to be a straight line development
直線的に発展していくように見える
That is to say, everything about me is actually
つまり、私のすべては実は
just go to the extreme
ただ極端に行くだけ
to pursue excellence
卓越性を追求する
But in another category
でも別のカテゴリーで
For example, between people
たとえば、人と人との間では、
that treat each other
お互いを扱うこと
it seems to go again
また行けそうだ
what we call oriental wisdom
私たちが東洋の知恵と呼ぶもの
treat each other
お互いを扱い合う
Then in these two cultures
そして、これら 2 つの文化では
In fact, when I was faced with a
実際、私が問題に直面したとき、
I'm going to make this sick
これを病気にしてやる
able to be cured
治すことができる
or make this
またはこれを作ります
I can push this thing further
これをさらに推し進めることができます
or people care about me
あるいは人々が私のことを気にかけてくれる
when you can get along
仲良くなれるとき
In fact, what we focus on
実際、私たちが注力しているのは、
is the same thing
是同一個東西
just say in the method
メソッド内で言うだけです
or conceptually
あるいは概念的に
is there a difference
違いはありますか
But in fact
しかし実際には
I'm fighting a judgment now
私は今判決を争っています
I don't know what Mr. Lei thinks about this
レイさんがこの件についてどう思っているかは分かりませんが、
Do you have any opinion on this?
これについて何か意見はありますか？
thanks for these two questions
2 つの質問をありがとう
The first question is to say
最初の質問はこう言います
We currently have very limited data
現在のところデータは非常に限られています
That means I can't rebuild
つまり再構築はできない
That is why it has such an idea
だからこそそのような考え方があるのです
But it should be the period of early rule with Taiwan
しかし、それは台湾との初期統治時代のはずです
The history of Chinese medicine in Taiwan at the beginning has a lot to do with it
台湾の中医学の始まりの歴史は大きく関係しています
that is to say actually
つまり実際には
At that time, those Chinese medicine practitioners were the first to come into contact with
当時、最初に接触したのはこれらの漢方医たちでした。
That is to say, people trained in modern science
つまり、現代科学の訓練を受けた人々です。
But we rarely talk about this part now
しかし、今ではこの部分について話すことはほとんどありません
Most of our history of medicine during the Japanese period is about
日本統治時代の医学の歴史のほとんどは、
The history of Western medicine rarely talks about the history of Chinese medicine
西洋医学の歴史では中医学の歴史について語られることはほとんどありません。
So this part is still very under under study
したがって、この部分はまだ研究中です
but i feel that
でも私はそう感じます
You can feel strongly from Du Congming's story
杜聡明の話から強く感じられること
He he he got inspiration with him over there
彼は彼と一緒にインスピレーションを得た
Then his discourse
それから彼の談話は
Because later it can't be realized
後になっては実現できないから
So there's really no way to trace his development.
したがって、彼の成長を追跡する方法は実際にはありません。
Then we can read him another
そうすれば、彼をもう一度読むことができます
I just talked about the class he gave after he went to the freshman year of high school
先ほど彼が高校一年生に上がった後の授業について話しました。
historical materials left behind
残された史料
but I
しかし、私
But I, I, I also doubt
でも私も私も疑ってしまう
Still can't fully answer your question
まだあなたの質問に完全には答えられません
Then your next question is to say
それでは、次の質問は次のようになります。
To supplement the one just now about
今のことを補足すると、
The significance of Ms. Tuyouyou's award in 15 years
トゥヨウヨウさんの15年ぶりの受賞の意義
In fact, I should actually say that I was
実際、私は実際にそうだったと言うべきです
I'm going to test that Yangming business
陽明のビジネスをテストしてみます
The name is Luochunshan, and then I went to study physiology
名前は羅春山、その後生理学を学びに行きました
So basically I'm in the background of Physiology
基本的に私は生理学を専攻しています
rather than the background of the catechism
要理問答の背景ではなく、
But that award-winning story of the young lady
しかし、受賞歴のある若い女性の物語は、
just let me at least from the media
少なくともメディアからは出させてください
It can be seen from relevant information
関連情報からも分かります
first sure
まず確かに
The Nobel is to be awarded to that party
ノーベル賞はその政党に授与されることになっている
It is the method of extracting Qinghao tree
青葉樹の抽出方法です
The reason for that method
その方法の理由
According to Ms.
女史によると、
It is the one from the Northern and Southern Dynasties
南北朝時代のものです
Ge Hong's book about clothes
ゲー・ホンの服に関する本
Then he compared him with this modern
それから彼は彼をこの現代のものと比較しました
scientific knowledge connects it
科学的知識がそれを結びつける
That's why the Qinghao tree was able to come out
だからこそ青暈の木が出てくることができた
I think this is a supplement
これは補足だと思います
as if to say
まるで言うかのように
But for Ms. Tuyouyou's winner
しかし、トゥヨウヨウさんの勝者にとっては
he will feel that yes
彼はそうだと感じるだろう
Nobel
ノーベル
The Nobel Prize is to honor this China and North Korea
ノーベル賞はこの中国と北朝鮮を讃えるものである
But for the Nobel Committee
しかしノーベル委員会にとっては
it's not actually
実際にはそうではありません
It actually shows that, as the New York Times puts it,
ニューヨーク・タイムズ紙が述べているように、それは実際に次のことを示しています。
is that it is actually an ordinary scientific study
それは実際には普通の科学研究だということです
found a new drug
新しい薬を見つけた
in an innovative way
革新的な方法で
Found a drug that is extremely effective against abusers
乱用者に対して非常に効果的な薬を発見
So these two seem
それでこの二人はどうやら
Maybe it's right for Tu Nv
たぶんそれはTu Nvに適しています
As far as native girls are concerned
ネイティブの女の子に関する限り
Its interpretation of the study goes like this
研究の解釈は次のようになります
Westerners have different ideas from Westerners
西洋人は西洋人とは異なる考えを持っています
Just to make such a supplement
ただそのような補足をするために
so you said
それであなたは言いました
yes, that's what i think
はい、それが私が思うことです
the rights of others
他人の権利
Then you just said
それからあなたは今言いました
It learned from Ge Hong
ゲーホンから学びました
That is to say, one foot has limbs
つまり、片方の足に手足があるということです。
So I thought of low temperature extraction
そこで低温抽出を考えました
that this is indeed relevant
これは確かに関連性があるということ
but if so
しかし、もしそうなら
This connection is also weak, isn't it?
このつながりも弱いですよね。
That is to say, it is probably like this
つまり多分こんな感じです
But I'm going the other way
でも私は違う道を行く
The one behind you just spoke longer
あなたの後ろの人はただ長く話しました
Then there is the question of
次に、次の質問があります。
I turned it into another related question
別の関連質問に変えました
that is
あれは
you see my story
私の話がわかりますか
My stories are all about success
私の物語はすべて成功についてです
right
右
Then others can say the other way around
そうすれば、他の人は逆のことを言うことができます
Then you know that Du Congming will drive a few more
そうすれば、Du Congming がさらに数台運転することがわかります。
Will our research be successful right away?
私たちの研究はすぐに成功するでしょうか?
I don't think Du Congming will be so sure
杜聡明がそこまで確信するとは思えない
So there are critics who say
だからこう言う批評家もいる
For example, the young lady just mentioned that someone went to Merc, right?
たとえば、先ほど若い女性がメルクに行った人がいるとおっしゃいましたよね。
In fact, the one I just talked about in Xiehe Hospital
実は、先ほど話した謝河病院のことです。
Then they made ephedrine
それから彼らはエフェドリンを作りました
Ephedrine can cure asthma
エフェドリンは喘息を治すことができる
And that was the general period of the Republic of China
それが中華民国の一般的な時代でした
Research considered a true breakthrough
真の画期的な研究と考えられる
He was later poached by the Lilai Pharmaceutical Factory
その後、彼は麗来製薬工場に密猟された
as their research director
研究ディレクターとして
Then he became the first academician of Academia Sinica
その後、彼は中央研究院の最初の学者になりました。
So that's actually another person
ということは、実は別人なんですね
But after he went to reason
しかし、彼が理性を持った後、
we didn't hear that
私たちはそれを聞いていません
Another big breakthrough, right?
また大きな進歩ですね？
then why
それでなんで
Logically speaking, we imagined
論理的に言えば、私たちが想像したのは、
he got to a place
彼はある場所に到着した
Lilai Pharmaceutical Factory fully supports him
麗来製薬工場は彼を全面的にサポートします
Then he became the director for decades
それから彼は数十年間監督を務めました
best environment
最高の環境
Why is there no research result?
なぜ研究結果が出ていないのでしょうか？
So someone would say the other way around
だから誰かは逆のことを言うだろう
maybe there's something of value over there
もしかしたらそこに価値のあるものがあるかもしれない
but something of value
でも価値のあるもの
Maybe not as much as we think
私たちが思っているほどではないかもしれません
I'm sorry everyone today
みなさん今日はごめんなさい
I have been trying to repeat the positions of both sides in
私は両国の立場を繰り返してみました。
keep him active in our minds over and over again
彼を私たちの心の中で何度も繰り返し活動させてください
because i feel like i said
言った気がするから
This period of history is indeed still developing and controversial.
この時代の歴史は、確かにまだ発展途上であり、議論の余地のある歴史です。
Even Du Congming would take a
杜聡明ですら、
The hope that is embraced and the attitude that overcomes the fear
抱く希望と恐怖を乗り越える姿勢
Then I personally stand in this position
それから私は個人的にこの立場に立っています
to write this history
この歴史を書くために
so i feel like saying
だから言いたい気がする
I am indeed the same as Du Congming
私はまさに杜聡明と同じです
because of hope
希望があるから
So I will study these seriously
なので、真剣に勉強してみます
History of Proven Success
実証された成功の歴史
so that the kind of origin of our story
それで、私たちの物語の起源のようなもの
I think it is because based on the development of science now
それは今の科学の発展に基づいているからだと思います
The old thing was that we completely broke with him
以前は彼とは完全に別れていた。
he must be worthless
彼は価値のない人間に違いない
There is absolutely no need to give up
諦める必要は全くありません
I think that position is problematic
その立場には問題があると思う
But does it mean
でもそれって意味あるの？
On the other side there is a very large vault
反対側にはとても大きな金庫があります
or a completely different way of thinking
あるいは全く異なる考え方
That is to say, this is another question
つまり、これは別の質問です
then i don't...
それなら私はしません...
That's me as a history student
それが歴史学生としての私です
I want to be special...
特別になりたい…
In particular, take a more cautious stance
特に、より慎重な姿勢をとる
to discover the attitudes of this study
この研究の姿勢を知るために
So I deliberately echo everyone's opinions on the one hand.
そこで、私は意図的にみんなの意見を反映させます。
On the other hand, some opposing opinions
一方で反対意見も
Come for your reference
参考までにどうぞ
OK nothing else
OK、他には何もありません
question
問題
yes over there
はい、あそこです
Let me reply to the paragraph just now
今の段落に返信させてください
That is to say, one of our partners just talked about
つまり、私たちのパートナーの一人が今話したのですが、
just need some time to use
使用するのに少し時間が必要です
Other unapproved medicines are effective
他の未承認薬も効果あり
Then this part actually you push it back
次に、この部分を実際に押し戻します
This is also the biggest advantage in Chinese medicine
これが漢方医学の最大の利点でもあります
I just have used it for thousands of years
何千年も使ってきただけ
there are some medicines
いくつかの薬があります
It has produced some clinical effects
いくつかの臨床効果をもたらしました
That's confirmed that its possible interactions won't kill
可能性のある相互作用によって死亡しないことが確認されました
So on such a basis
ですから、そのようなベースに基づいて
If it is developed from its medicinal effect
その薬効から開発された場合
find out which part of the word it might work
どの部分が機能する可能性があるかを調べる
The so-called reverse research
いわゆる逆リサーチ
it becomes ill to soto
ソトに病気になる
How many people do you have to die to find a new drug
新薬を見つけるために何人死ななければなりませんか
this may be one of the
これはそのうちの1つかもしれません
I think Han Yi is in the research
ハン・イは研究中だと思う
He made me a data base
彼は私にデータベースを作ってくれました
a good starting point
良い出発点
I suddenly thought of someone I could ask you for advice
突然、あなたにアドバイスを求められる人を思い出しました
It is an open trial that has been done for thousands of years in the past
過去何千年にもわたって行われてきた公開の試みです
open trial is also
オープントライアルも
And now I think it’s time to do double blind placebo
そして今は二重盲検プラセボを行う時期だと思う
So I did this in Xili
それで私はXiliでこれをしました
it is open
それが開いています
Or open lab use
またはオープンラボでの使用
or it was the beginning
あるいはそれが始まりだった
try to see if it works
うまくいくかどうか試してみる
It was open at that time
その時は開いてました
so in fact
だから実際のところ
I also said that the history above helped to open it
上記の歴史がそれを開くのに役立ったとも言いました
think it works
うまくいくと思う
Otherwise there is no evidence at all
そうでなければ証拠が全くない
say try it
試してみてと言う
not like this
こんなんじゃない
so i think over here he sees this
だからここで彼はこれを見ていると思う
So in fact there is quite a lot of evidence
実際にはかなり多くの証拠があります
this is very promising
これは非常に有望です
he wants to push
彼は押したいのです
you'll talk about it later
それについては後で話します
I just want to learn my experience
自分の経験を学びたいだけです
is sorry
ごめんなさい
I want to go back to that big brother Bran just now
今すぐあのブランお兄さんのところに戻りたい
I want to study the law
法律を勉強したいです
We cannot fall into this Western medicine
私たちはこの西洋医学に陥ることはできません
that subject
その主題
Because of traditional Chinese medicine, make Dazu Bolan
伝統的な中国医学のため、ダズボーランを作ります
it has an inherent difficulty
それには固有の難しさがある
i just wanted to say yes
はいと言いたかっただけです
This is Western medicine with that
これが西洋医学です
Then you have to do Cleaner Trial
次に、クリーナートライアルを実行する必要があります
Cleaner Trial words
クリーナートライアルワード
In fact, the traditional Chinese medicine
実は、伝統的な中国医学では、
how to do the best
最善を尽くす方法
i'm not here to discuss
私は議論するためにここにいるわけではありません
i just say yes
私はただ「はい」と言うだけです
In fact it is
実際そうなのです
If it was him
彼だったら
When people criticize
人が批判するとき
He said it's actually been done
彼はそれが実際に行われたと言いました
It's not like experimenting on humans
人体実験とは違います
Then you are an experiment
じゃあ君も実験台だよ
He actually doesn't have this at all
彼は実際にはこれをまったく持っていません
suddenly remembered
突然思い出した
This seems to be useful today
今日はこれが役に立ちそうです
no evidence
証拠がない
I just talked about Evidence
先ほど証拠について話しました
Actually maybe not
実際にはそうではないかもしれない
But for thousands of years
しかし、何千年もの間、
there is
がある
It made him feel confident
それは彼に自信を与えた
So the point is
それでポイントは
Maybe I didn't get Appreciation from others at the beginning
最初は他人から感謝されなかったのかもしれない
but maybe this is the reason
でもおそらくこれが理由です
will try to push over there
そこに押し込もうとするだろう
What I was going to say just now is the double-blind talk
今言おうとしていたのはダブルブラインドトークです
In Chinese medicine, because the medicine in Chinese medicine has its own taste
漢方では、漢方の薬には独自の味があるため、
So if we use the method of Western medicine to study
では、西洋医学の方法で勉強してみると、
Can't use double blind
ダブルブラインドは使えません
Because the patient knows that the taste is different
患者は味が違うことを知っているから
But if it is Chinese medicine
でも漢方薬なら
do you want to ask you
聞きたいですか？
That is to say, it is Chinese medicine, right?
つまり漢方薬ですよね？
Or should we go to the scientific side?
それとも科学側に進むべきでしょうか？
If it is extracted
抽出された場合
that's more hopeful
そのほうが希望が持てる
If you use scientific Chinese medicine, that step is fine.
科学的な漢方を使えば、そのステップは大丈夫です。
It should be going that way
そうなるはずだ
the shorter the distance
距離が短いほど
At present, scientific Chinese medicine has a certain evalence
現在、科学的な中国医学は一定の価値を持っています
over there
そちら側
That is to say, there are some schemes to do it this way.
つまり、このようにするためのいくつかのスキームがあります。
it does work
それは機能します
Okay, so we're running out of time.
さて、時間がなくなりました。
so i think
だから私は思う
I will first enounce
まず宣言します
It's the next month next time
次回は来月です
just support
ただサポートするだけ
The program I want to try is in October
やってみたいプログラムは10月です
It's our side
それは私たちの側です
Cai Dingping of the hard science center of Songyuan Academy
松原学院ハードサイエンスセンターの蔡鼎平氏
Special Review Researcher and Director
特別審査研究員兼ディレクター
Lecturer on this new era of photonics
フォトニクス新時代の講師
should be a very good speech
とても良いスピーチになるはずです
I hope you will sign up
登録していただければ幸いです
OK then we are very grateful this time
はい、では今回は本当にありがとうございました
Dr. Ray shared with us this
レイ博士は私たちにこのことを教えてくれました
This is a very wonderful historical story
これはとても素晴らしい歴史的な物語です
we have a lot to inspire
私たちにはインスピレーションを与えるものがたくさんあります
There's a lot to think about
考えるべきことがたくさんあります
Is it a round of applause? Thank you.
拍手ですか?ありがとうございます。
Thank him
彼に感謝します